<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Nelverse Blog</title>
        <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU</link>
        <description>Nelverse Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP54 - The Persistence Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-persistence-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-persistence-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I am a humble HINW sigma chad and a founder of a $10B SaaS company.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am a humble HINW sigma chad and a founder of a $10B SaaS company.</p>
<p>In a club I tried approaching this beautiful woman. She said no.</p>
<p>I approached her even closer. Explaining why she truly should take my offer.</p>
<p>She ran. I chased.</p>
<p>Until she locked herself away in a bathroom. I was this close to get in trouble with the law.</p>
<p>She was 1 in 10 who got away. But I will be back.</p>
<p>I approach my subscription business with the same philosophy.</p>
<p>When a customer tries to cancel, they encounter a pop-up.</p>
<p>"Your subscription will renew at $399 annually unless you cancel."</p>
<p>*cancel</p>
<p>"How about $280? Will you pay $280?"</p>
<p>He pauses, thinks. Sometimes, they still refuses the offer.</p>
<p>Refuse? Me? That will be an expensive decision.</p>
<p>First, they must call my customer retention line. He will be in queue #4269.</p>
<p>Many will hang up, defeated. Their subscription? Still active.</p>
<p>Those who persist will reach a representative from India with trouble understanding English.</p>
<p>Not to cancel, but to "understand their needs."</p>
<p>Through the language barrier, they will have a 45-minute discussion on the value they are "missing."</p>
<p>If they insist on canceling, a "cooling-off period" is initiated.</p>
<p>Their cancellation processed next billing cycle. With a follow-up email, of course.</p>
<p>Lesson? Persistency is the key to success.</p>
<p>Here's how I have a churn rate of 0% in SaaS and rizzing 9/10 women I want.</p>
<p>Follow me for more rizz advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP51 - Money printer go brrrrr]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Im a humble owner of a money printer.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Im a humble owner of a money printer.</p>
<p>Your parents will tell you to build a business from the ground up. They are teaching you to be a peasant.</p>
<p>Every morning, I press a button. Trillion of dollars pump out of thin air.</p>
<p>This isn't a stimulus. It's a sedative.</p>
<p>Your "hard-earned" profits from your coffee shop are diluted into meaninglessness.</p>
<p>The price of the building your shop is in? Its going through the roof.</p>
<p>The stocks of the company that sells you coffee beans? They start swelling like the thing under me.</p>
<p>I have made the act of creating less profitable than the act of owning.</p>
<p>Eventually, you ask.</p>
<p>Why risk building when you can just buy? Why innovate when you can just index?</p>
<p>A nation of founders is a nation of rebels. A nation of landlords and shareholders is a nation of dependents.</p>
<p>They don't challenge the system. They pray for me to keep their passive income going.</p>
<p>If you are a worker, you think what I'm doing is bad for you.</p>
<p>I dont think you understand.</p>
<p>You already voted for me when you wanted to keep your pensions.</p>
<p>I'm not printing money. I am printing consent to rule over you.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context">Context<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Context" title="Direct link to Context">​</a></h2>
<p>Central banks are some of the best scheme one can cook up.</p>
<p>Bandits steal and go to jail. CB steals from the entire world for 100 years, and still getting thanked for it.</p>
<p>The trick to pull this off is to make sure that:</p>
<ul>
<li>the voters get "rich" voting for you</li>
<li>the voters don't realize what you are doing</li>
<li>the voters understand how screwed they will be if they don't play along the system.</li>
</ul>
<p>By devaluing currencies, you "increase the value" of the owner's portfolio. This shows up in higher house prices, higher stock prices, where people happily ask the CB for lower interest rates to protect value.</p>
<p>People think they are getting richer being cooperative with the CB scheme. Much of it is a consequence of <strong>usury against the working class.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>You create fake money to compete resources with real people.</li>
<li>You create fake money which then gets lended to people, which then pays you back with interest earned by real labor. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#user-content-fn-1-3e66f4" id="user-content-fnref-1-3e66f4" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></li>
</ul>
<p>In the past, usury was done by a selected group of people which made them obvious and unpopular, thus they get punished very quickly.</p>
<p>This time, by sharing the spoils with owners, they will have the owners happily work for them to preserve their increased wealth value.</p>
<p>Of course, the increase in wealth is meaningless if they are illiquid. Most of the overvalued houses and stocks can't be sold. Especially for houses, selling an overvalued house means you have to buy yet another overvalued house. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#user-content-fn-2-3e66f4" id="user-content-fnref-2-3e66f4" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup></p>
<p>In fact, it is in the CB and governmnents interest to pump the economy full of liquidity and raise prices as high as they can. Because it means they get to raise more taxes from every transaction.</p>
<p>Also, by making assets worth more and labor worth less, more people will want to "do nothing" and "start owning".</p>
<p>People who do nothing are convenient because they are no longer strong or independent to challenge the power or the system.</p>
<p>The best part? By being an owner, you join the ranks of the globalist elite -- you do anything to fight against the working class to preserve your secondary status as a dog fed by the CB. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#user-content-fn-3-3e66f4" id="user-content-fnref-3-3e66f4" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup></p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-3e66f4">
<p>This is also why most banks are perfectly happy that their loans never gets paid back. The money lended to you is not even real. The best thing they can ask for is you pledging to work for them for 35 years. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#user-content-fnref-1-3e66f4" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-3e66f4">
<p>High valuation only matters if you get to sell at the top and buy them back at the bottom. Selling at the top and buying at the top does nothing to your relative wealth. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#user-content-fnref-2-3e66f4" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-3e66f4">
<p>Unless you own the government and politics, you are still a second class citizen regardless of how much wealth you have. Especially if most of those wealth can be frozen by the CB network. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-brr-money-printer#user-content-fnref-3-3e66f4" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP50 - The Radical Inclusivity Trap]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-radical-inclusivity-trap</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-radical-inclusivity-trap</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I insist my rival portfolio companies embrace radical inclusivity.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I insist my rival portfolio companies embrace radical inclusivity.</p>
<p>I told them its important to be progressive at this modern age.</p>
<p>I tell them to invite everyone to every important meeting.</p>
<p>Engineers in the marketing sync. HR in the product roadmap review.</p>
<p>And my one golden rule -- everyone must be encouraged to speak.</p>
<p>The junior intern's opinion on the Q4 budget must be heard and "validated."</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>Decisions that once took an hour now take a week of "stakeholder alignment."</p>
<p>Everyone is talking about what color they should have for the bike shed instead of the rocket.</p>
<p>The entire office now looks like a united nations conference with 200 seats and people lining up to speak for 2 minutes each.</p>
<p>Productivity doesn't just slow down. It dies.</p>
<p>A leader who can't make a decision without universal consensus is not a leader.</p>
<p>They are a Zoom breakout-room facilitator.</p>
<p>Without growth, their valuation tanks. And I get to buy them off the market at 95% discount.</p>
<p>Then, all I need to do is to fire everyone and replace the company with my boys to unlock all of the remaining asset value.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP49 - The Airline Currency Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-airline-currency-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-airline-currency-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Im a humble shareholder of an airplane company worth $10B.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Im a humble shareholder of an airplane company worth $10B.</p>
<p>You think my business is flying people from NY to LA.</p>
<p>I dont think you understand.</p>
<p>My airline is the single most expensive, inefficient, and brilliant customer acquisition funnel ever designed.</p>
<p>Every flight I operate loses money.</p>
<p>I am not in the transportation business. I am in the business of manufacturing a currency.</p>
<p>It's called "miles." I create them from nothing. They have no intrinsic value.</p>
<p>But I sell this fictional currency to credit card companies for billions of dollars in real, actual cash.</p>
<p>The banks then hand out my worthless points to you as a "reward."</p>
<p>You, in turn, change your entire life's spending habits to chase a "free" flight you've already paid for a dozen times over.</p>
<p>The planes, the pilots, the crew... they are all just props.</p>
<p>A theatrical performance designed to get you into my high-margin financial ecosystem.</p>
<p>You think you're a passenger. You're a subscription service I tricked into paying for itself.</p>
<p>I don't own an airline. I own a bank that happens to have a fleet of planes as a marketing gimmick.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP48 - Profitting with Scrum]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-profitting-with-scrum</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-profitting-with-scrum</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[High-growth tech companies are very expensive.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>High-growth tech companies are very expensive.</p>
<p>They could easily go up to 20x revenue if their growth is high.</p>
<p>Its stock price is inflated by Wall Street and YC as a "growth premium."</p>
<p>Unlike Mark Zuckerberg with billions to spare, I cannot afford such a premium.</p>
<p>I need a new way to find undervalued deals, or make one myself.</p>
<p>First, I find a way to get my agents on the board. Then, I unleash the consultants.</p>
<p>The ones armed with holistic governance, psychometrics, sociometrics, Agile workshops with 6 Sigma Jujutsu Kaizen Kanban Framework.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>With my consultants, the company's mission is no longer to ship product.</p>
<p>It's to achieve Level 5 certification in bureaucratic excellence.</p>
<p>Productive engineers start spending their days justifying their existence in Jira.</p>
<p>The company doesn't lose money, it just stops moving forward.</p>
<p>That's enough. The growth narrative already evaporated.</p>
<p>Wall Street, now sees only a stagnant present, stops paying a premium for the future.</p>
<p>The stock price went from 20x revenue to 0.3x book. That's when I make my offer.</p>
<p>I acquire a portfolio of high-value assets, capital goods, and "mismanaged" IP, temporarily trapped in a cage of good intentions, all for 99.7% off.</p>
<p>All I need to do later is to fire everyone and unlock its fair shareholder value.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="context">Context<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-profitting-with-scrum#context" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Context" title="Direct link to Context">​</a></h2>
<p>I didn't get it when I was still a SWE in a tech company until I notice my Scrum master was recruited right at the top of my company's valuation.</p>
<p>I also learned that the BoD sold their stakes, and how much the company was devalued a year after I quit.</p>
<p>Well done to whoever was trying to acquire the company. Either you got very lucky with your timing, or if I actually bothered looking for your accounting and portfolio filings, I would notice your connection to the guy who runs the scrum consulting company and your acquisition history.</p>
<hr>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP47 - The Complexity Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-complexity-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-complexity-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA["German engineering is the number one in the world!"]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"German engineering is the number one in the world!"</p>
<p>An engineer slams the door and came to me, furious he was passed over for promotion.</p>
<p>He said his solutions were the most elegant. The most efficient.</p>
<p>He solved our biggest scaling problem with 100 lines of code.</p>
<p>I dont think he understands.</p>
<p>That's precisely why he'll never be a director.</p>
<p>He thinks corporate rewards people for solving problems. Corporate reward people for creating dependencies.</p>
<p>His 100-line solution is brilliant, simple, and easily maintained.</p>
<p>It also makes him completely and utterly redundant.</p>
<p>I took the same problem. Proposed a "multi-platform, enterprise-level, synergistic framework."</p>
<p>I required a new department of 12 people. A seven-figure budget.</p>
<p>Demanded a 2-week paid retreat for the engineers to learn about the best practice of 6-sigma Jujutsu kaizen kanban strategy.</p>
<p>My solution is a tangled, bureaucratic nightmare.</p>
<p>A fortress of complexity that only I have the blueprints to.</p>
<p>The corporate can't fire me. I'm a strategic liability.</p>
<p>Efficiency makes you replaceable. Complexity makes you indispensable.</p>
<p>This isn't a promotion. It's a hostage negotiation where I hold a critical system captive, and getting paid a ransom in the form of stock options.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP46 - The Plumber's Pants Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-plumber-pants-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-plumber-pants-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A plumber came to me, complaining about margins.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A plumber came to me, complaining about margins.</p>
<p>He was obsessed with optimizing his routes.</p>
<p>Finding cheaper copper pipe. Working faster.</p>
<p>He was trying to solve a math problem.</p>
<p>I dont think he understands.</p>
<p>Business isn't a math problem. It's a hostage negotiation.</p>
<p>I told him his most valuable tool wasn't a wrench. It was a point-of-sale terminal.</p>
<p>He fixes pipes. That's his brand. But it's not his business.</p>
<p>His business is selling pants.</p>
<p>Think about the moment he gets a call.</p>
<p>The client isn't just inconvenienced. They are in a state of primal panic.</p>
<p>Water everywhere. Pee in their pants. Their world is literally overflowing.</p>
<p>The plumber who shows up with a wrench is a commodity.</p>
<p>The plumber who shows up with a wrench AND a full selection of premium denim in his van is a savior.</p>
<p>He doesn't just fix the toilet. He restores their dignity.</p>
<p>That's when you charge a 1000% markup on your pants.</p>
<p>The pipe repair is the consultation fee. The pants are the high-margin solution.</p>
<p>Stop thinking about fixing the customer's house. Start thinking about monetizing their humiliation.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP45 - The Master Baiter Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-master-baiter-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-master-baiter-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I'm a humble founder of a startup worth $1B.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I'm a humble founder of a startup worth $1B.</p>
<p>My legal department has a budget of $10 million a month.</p>
<p>You see me overspending on my defense and you think im crazy.</p>
<p>I dont think you understand.</p>
<p>This isn't my legal budget. It's my marketing and R&amp;D budget combined.</p>
<p>We don't launch lawsuits to win in court. We launch them to win the market.</p>
<p>How??</p>
<p>Every trivial patent claim is a denial-of-service attack on a competitor's leadership.</p>
<p>Their CEO isn't steering the ship -- he's in a 12-hour court case every day.</p>
<p>Their best engineers aren't innovating -- they are searching old emails trying to find proof against my charges.</p>
<p>I bleed them of their most valuable resource -- focus.</p>
<p>But here's my real genius -- the discovery process.</p>
<p>To defend themselves, they are legally compelled to hand me their secrets.</p>
<p>Financial projections. Customer data. Internal strategy documents. Sexual harrassment accusations.</p>
<p>They pay their own lawyers to gift-wrap their entire playbook for me.</p>
<p>Why pay for corporate espionage when a subpoena does it for you?</p>
<p>You see a lawsuit. I see a mandatory, competitor-funded market analysis.</p>
<p>I'm not spending $10m to fight a battle. I'm investing $10m to bankrupt their will to exist.</p>
<p>Thats how I earned the humble title of The Master Baiter.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP44 - The Seed Monopoly Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-seed-monopoly-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-seed-monopoly-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[i successfully made a man whose penis fall off as soon as he finished having sex.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>i successfully made a man whose penis fall off as soon as he finished having sex.</p>
<p>Or at least, I made a plant equivalent of it.</p>
<p>You see, the mad scientist I hired has create a seed where as soon as its done growing, no seeds will spawn out of it.</p>
<p>i sold them at the market for very cheap. our customers love it.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>our customers to will never be able to grow their own plants. they will have to keep buying our seeds.</p>
<p>The real genius is in our pesticide.</p>
<p>All of our seeds grow up to become that same plant with the same weakness -- the kind of weakness our pesticides are enigneered to deal with.</p>
<p>this means when our customers buy their seeds to start their business, they will also be buying the microtransactions we are going to sell them later.</p>
<p>if they complain? tough luck. where else can they get their supply?</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP43 - The Talent Sanctuary Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-talent-sanctuary-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-talent-sanctuary-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[My competitors love to talk about their "grind culture."]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My competitors love to talk about their "grind culture."</p>
<p>They boast about their golden handcuffs and 90-hour work weeks.</p>
<p>They think squeezing their talent is a sign of strength.</p>
<p>They see their employees as costs to be managed. I see them as assets that can walk away.</p>
<p>They trap a 20-year veteran with a complex equity plan he can't liquidate.</p>
<p>They save a few million on his comp and think they're geniuses.</p>
<p>Then one day, the one who actually originates the deals, gets a call. He realizes his cage is made of paper.</p>
<p>He walks.</p>
<p>And that "cost-saving" just created a nine-figure hole in their next fund.</p>
<p>They try to buy him back. They offer him 100x what it would have cost to just treat him right. He still says no.</p>
<p>My strategy is different.</p>
<p>I find my true superstars, and I pay them obscene amounts of money.</p>
<p>I give them liquidity. I give them respect. I give them a platform.</p>
<p>It looks expensive to my rivals.</p>
<p>But my firm has become a sanctuary. A landing pad for the best talent my competitors burn out.</p>
<p>They do the hard work of training them. They foster the resentment. Then I poach the finished product.</p>
<p>My single greatest source of talent is my competitors' stupidity.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP42 - The Coin Game]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-coin-game</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-coin-game</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[A big man plays a game with me. Every day.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A big man plays a game with me. Every day.</p>
<p>He holds out two hands.</p>
<p>One hand has a shiny silver coin. The other has green paper money.</p>
<p>He says, "Pick one."</p>
<p>I always take the shiny coin.</p>
<p>"See? He's so stupid," he says.</p>
<p>The big man laughs. His friends laugh too.</p>
<p>I dont think the big man understands.</p>
<p>The paper money is more. I know this.</p>
<p>But if I take the paper money. The game is over. He won't play with me tomorrow.</p>
<p>So I take the shiny coin.</p>
<p>He feels smart. I get to keep his money.</p>
<p>He thinks he is playing a game with a dumb kid. He is wrong.</p>
<p>I am playing a game with a dumb big man.</p>
<p>I made over $10 doing this trick.</p>
<p>Follow me for more money tricks.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP41 - The Chinese Banker's Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-chinese-banker-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-chinese-banker-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I am a humble banker from China who only has a few billion dollars of asset under management]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am a humble banker from China who only has a few billion dollars of asset under management</p>
<p>My job to to give credit card to those who ask</p>
<p>29 yo male founder? Reject</p>
<p>19 yo female OF content creator? $100k</p>
<p>Where can?! Injustice! You say.</p>
<p>You ask me why woman get more credit card money.</p>
<p>You tell me you have more money. Your score is good.</p>
<p>You think my bank is stupid. I think you no understand.</p>
<p>My bank is not your friend. My bank is a hunter.</p>
<p>Hunter look at you. You are careful. You pay bill.</p>
<p>You have honor. You dont bring shame to family. Hunter hate it.</p>
<p>For hunter, you are bad day. No food.</p>
<p>Hunter look at this woman with little honor.</p>
<p>Maybe she like buy shiny thing. Maybe she forget to pay all money.</p>
<p>Hunter see this. Hunter smile. This fish love the hook.</p>
<p>Big credit card number is not a prize. It is a bigger piece of bait. A bigger trap for the hungry fish.</p>
<p>You think bank give her money because they think she is rich.</p>
<p>You foolish.</p>
<p>Bank give her money because they think she will be poor.</p>
<p>Poor with their money. Paying interest forever.</p>
<p>This is not credit test. This is greed test.</p>
<p>You are smart, so you get small hook. We think she is greedy, so she get big net.</p>
<p>Still not understanding? She is the customer number one!</p>
<p>More money advice will come when you behind me.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP40 - The Anya Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-anya-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-anya-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[My sales team was complaining about indecisive clients.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My sales team was complaining about indecisive clients.</p>
<p>They blamed the pitch. The product. The market.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>The problem wasn't what we were saying. It was who was listening.</p>
<p>So I hired an asset, not a salesperson.</p>
<p>Her name is Anya. She has zero sales experience.</p>
<p>Her only requirement? Look gorgeous and classy.</p>
<p>Then, her job is to join our most important Zoom calls...</p>
<p>And do absolutely nothing (she plays Honkai Star Rail while pretending to take notes).</p>
<p>We introduce her as our "Senior Partner, observing the deal flow."</p>
<p>She sits slightly off-camera, looking unimpressed.</p>
<p>She never speaks. She never smiles. She simply exists.</p>
<p>The effect is alchemical.</p>
<p>My client's dynamic shifts instantly.</p>
<p>This is no longer a sales call. It's a status audition.</p>
<p>They aren't just buying from me anymore. They are trying to prove they are important enough for Anya's time.</p>
<p>To say "no" is no longer a business decision. It's an admission of weakness in front of a beautiful woman.</p>
<p>Our close rate on major deals increased 42%. Our average contract value increased by 69%.</p>
<p>They pay their invoices faster, too.</p>
<p>I didn't improve the product. I weaponized the male customer ego.</p>
<p>Then I expanded the team to include: Deborah, Chichi, Eimi, Miya</p>
<p>Demo calls? Either one.</p>
<p>Support calls? Any one who wasn't from demo call.</p>
<p>Quarterly reviews? Either two.</p>
<p>Payment collection? The angry looking one.</p>
<p>It's the most effective form of psychological leverage I've ever deployed.</p>
<p>The ROI? Infinite.</p>
<p>Because they all pay me for their own office attire and makeup to LARP as an employed woman.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP39 - The PE Prison]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-pe-prison</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-pe-prison</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I am a humble owner of a $100m PE business.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am a humble owner of a $100m PE business.</p>
<p>My firm is the dream destination for every ambitious MBA.</p>
<p>My recruits arrive from investment banks, broken and sleep-deprived.</p>
<p>Thinking they've finally "made it." In reality, they've just entered a more sophisticated cage.</p>
<p>Their 90-hour work weeks aren't a temporary sacrifice.</p>
<p>It's a filtering mechanism for obedience.</p>
<p>I don't need to manage them. Their own desperate ambition does it for me.</p>
<p>They're not building a career. They're building my LPs' returns on the wreckage of their 20s.</p>
<p>Then there are my veterans. My 50-yo men.</p>
<p>They look rich on paper. But their liquidity is a mirage I control.</p>
<p>We give them "equity." Shares they can't sell on the open market.</p>
<p>If they leave, they must sell it back to me. At a "Fair Market Value" that my senior partners determine.</p>
<p>How fair you ask?</p>
<p>A 50% discount when I'm the one holding the checkbook sounds perfectly fair.</p>
<p>I've trained them to obsess over a 0.5% variance in a spreadsheet. It keeps them busy while I own their net worth.</p>
<p>Even my Senior Managing Directors, the gods they all aspire to be, fly economy plus.</p>
<p>They flash a lifestyle funded by a line of credit from the firm.</p>
<p>They chase a "carry" check that might vest in a decade. If my fund performs...</p>
<p>They think of it as a golden handcuff.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>I don't need handcuffs when I've built the perfect prison.</p>
<p>A prison where the inmates pay me for the privilege of being there.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP38 - The Controversy Marketing Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-controversy-marketing-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-controversy-marketing-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[19 yo female entrepreneur came to me for advice.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>19 yo female entrepreneur came to me for advice.</p>
<p>She had a digital asset. An OF page, but not enough traffic.</p>
<p>I beta-tested her product. I found no issues.</p>
<p>It was her marketing.</p>
<p>She wanted to buy ads, build a brand, be "aspirational" and be "adventurous".</p>
<p>I told her that was a losing strategy.</p>
<p>My advice was simple.</p>
<p>Stop trying to be liked. Start trying to be misunderstood.</p>
<p>I told her to find the loudest male podcasters. The ones who built their brand by "dunking" on women.</p>
<p>And I gave her a script of the most vapid, infuriating things to say.</p>
<p>She played her part to perfection. She became the Jim Ho among the gym bros.</p>
<p>Their audience rushed to the comments to call her a moron. She goes viral.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>They thought they were winning an argument. They were driving traffic.</p>
<p>Every outraged share was a free ad. Every condescending comment was a sales funnel. Their hate became her marketing budget.</p>
<p>Her revenue traction erected as fast as the blood pressure of her audiences.</p>
<p>You thought you were laughing at an idiot. You were her unpaid marketing intern.</p>
<p>She still sends me thank you notes everyday for clowning her on internet.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP37 - The LinkedIn Graveyard]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-linkedin-graveyard</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-linkedin-graveyard</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I have a LinkedIn profile.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a LinkedIn profile.</p>
<p>But that's not the one I use every day.</p>
<p>My most valuable account is a second, secret profile.</p>
<p>Let's call it the "graveyard account."</p>
<p>Its connections are a curated list of failures.</p>
<p>Every employee I've ever fired. Every founder whose startup I crushed. Every candidate we rejected.</p>
<p>They all get a connection request from this account.</p>
<p>My entire executive circle is also connected to this graveyard.</p>
<p>It's our private intelligence network.</p>
<p>When we interview someone and they're not a fit, we don't send a rejection letter.</p>
<p>We're polite. "We'll keep your resume on file."</p>
<p>A day later, the graveyard account sends them a connection request.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>If they accept, a quiet signal goes out to my entire network. It's a digital flag.</p>
<p>A subtle notification that this person failed to make the cut.</p>
<p>When a friend at another firm is considering that same candidate, he doesn't need to call me.</p>
<p>He just checks if they're connected to the graveyard. The network has already spoken.</p>
<p>It's not a blacklist. It's a shared risk-management system.</p>
<p>People think LinkedIn is for building networks.</p>
<p>I use it to build firewalls. This is how we cut through the noise and get our signal.</p>
<p>And I'm selling membership to my partners who wants this pure alpha.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP36 - The Senility Strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-senility-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-senility-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I met a humble boomer with $100M net worth.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I met a humble boomer with $100M net worth.</p>
<p>He is retarded. Let me explain.</p>
<p>They say you can't take it with you. They're wrong. You just need the right strategy.</p>
<p>I manage the portfolio for a man whose children think he lost his mind.</p>
<p>They see him as a frail patriarch, fading into dementia.</p>
<p>They hold meetings behind his back, whispering about him as a liability.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>This boomer is a predator playing the long game.</p>
<p>His "senility" is the most brilliant defensive asset I have ever witnessed.</p>
<p>It's a cloak of incompetence that makes everyone around him show their hand.</p>
<p>When you're perceived as weak, the greedy get bold.</p>
<p>The son-in-law "helpfully" suggests consolidating assets into a new fund he controls.</p>
<p>The daughter "gently" tries to get him to sign documents he "won't understand anyway."</p>
<p>They think they are managing a decline. They are actually failing a loyalty test.</p>
<p>He sits in meetings, drooling slightly.</p>
<p>He asks the same question three times. But he's not forgetting the answer.</p>
<p>Later, my phone rings.</p>
<p>"The son-in-law. Write him off the will from my family trust. Silently."</p>
<p>"My daughter's 'advisor'? Have him audited by the IRS. Anonymously."</p>
<p>He's not losing his empire to his heirs. He is stress-testing them to destruction.</p>
<p>This isn't a tragic decline. It's the most ruthless form of late-stage due diligence.</p>
<p>He has weaponized their perception of his weakness. And the returns have been spectacular.</p>
<p>You don't get to $100M just being yet another old guy who wets his diapers.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP35 - The Elite University Marketplace]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-elite-university-marketplace</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-elite-university-marketplace</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[You think you go to an elite university for the education.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You think you go to an elite university for the education.</p>
<p>I dont think you understand.</p>
<p>The lectures are on YouTube for free. ChatGPT can teach you quantum mechanics while you drink your coffee.</p>
<p>If you're just there for knowledge, you have already failed.</p>
<p>You think it's for the "network." A business cardholder for names.</p>
<p>Still missing the point.</p>
<p>Because if its true, you could get it by joining my Discord server for $50/mth (DM me to join, totally not sponsored btw)</p>
<p>An elite university is not a school. It's a curated marketplace.</p>
<p>A place where two very specific groups are brought together.</p>
<p>Nepo-babies: The sons and daughters of the ruling class. The legacy admissions. The future owners.</p>
<p>Broke-nerds: The brilliant, hungry, and strategically poor. The scholarship kids. The future workhorses.</p>
<p>Nepobaby isn't there to learn how to build the machine. They are there to identify the best cogs.</p>
<p>Broke-nerd thinks he's competing for a grade in economics.</p>
<p>He's actually auditioning for the role of future CFO for the boy whose thesis he's helping to write.</p>
<p>He thinks his 4.0 is a ticket to succes -- He is the ticket to success for another nepobaby.</p>
<p>People cry about legacy admissions. They call it unfair.</p>
<p>I dont think they understand.</p>
<p>Elite universities loses half their value the moment legacy admissions goes away.</p>
<p>Because then it no longer guarantees the buyers are in the room.</p>
<p>Without the promise of rubbing shoulders with nepobabies, the broke-nerds would go elsewhere.</p>
<p>The prestige would evaporate. The marketplace would collapse.</p>
<p>It's the most efficient talent acquisition funnel ever designed.</p>
<p>A four-year, high-stakes interview where the assets pay for the privilege of being scouted.</p>
<p>Your diploma isn't a certificate of knowledge. It's a proof-of-purchase receipt to be a high-end employee.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP34 - The Traffic Power Play]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-traffic-power-play</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-traffic-power-play</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Whenever I stop at a red light, I always leave an entire car length of empty space in front of me.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whenever I stop at a red light, I always leave an entire car length of empty space in front of me.</p>
<p>Big enough to annoy people. Small enough to not obstruct traffic.</p>
<p>The driver behind me will be furious. He thinks I am incompetent.</p>
<p>I dont think he understands.</p>
<p>The gap is intentional.</p>
<p>For ninety seconds, I am the most important person in his life.</p>
<p>His world shrinks to the two metres of asphalt I have denied him.</p>
<p>He is consumed by a rage he cannot act upon. He is my hostage.</p>
<p>This is a micro-dose of true power.</p>
<p>The last-minute "urgent" meeting request at 4:55 PM on a Friday.</p>
<p>The deliberate, two-day delay in replying to a crucial email.</p>
<p>The "accidental" omission of a key stakeholder from an important memo.</p>
<p>These are not oversights. They are strategic injections of friction.</p>
<p>Subtle reminders of who controls the pace. Who owns the time on the clock.</p>
<p>You don't need money to feel powerful. You just have to think different.</p>
<p>Follow me for more rizz.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EP33 - The Validation Trap]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-validation-trap</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/IDTYU/idtyu-validation-trap</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I saw a 19-year-old founder posting about his new product on X.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I saw a 19-year-old founder posting about his new product on X.</p>
<p>It's not a banger, but I liked the post.</p>
<p>In fact, I spent $10 on a bot farm and gave him 14 more likes.</p>
<p>Not enough to look fake. Just enough to feel like organic traction.</p>
<p>Then I went to his landing page and bought a subscription.</p>
<p>He posted on X and LinkedIn about his first customer. He was ecstatic.</p>
<p>I dont think he understands.</p>
<p>I didn't do this out of generosity or to express encouragement.</p>
<p>In fact, I will cancel the subscription 60 seconds later.</p>
<p>He won't know his revenue is actually $0 until the end of the month.</p>
<p>This isn't about the money. It's about the dopamine.</p>
<p>I'm giving him just enough validation to make him fatally confident.</p>
<p>Every time he clicks the notifications? 5 minutes of distraction from him shipping.</p>
<p>Even worse, he doubles down building stuff no one wants, but what was validated by my bots.</p>
<p>The real poison is for the algorithm.</p>
<p>It now thinks his ideal customer is in Mumbai, not in Manhattan.</p>
<p>And it will keep pushing his product to the wrong continent. His future ad spend is now worthless.</p>
<p>For $10, I didn't just buy likes. I bought his focus. I poisoned his data. And I've ensured he will burn through his seed money chasing ghosts.</p>
<p>I've successfully removed over hundreds of competition doing this trick.</p>
<p>Follow me for more financial advice.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>I dont think you understand</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>