<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="atom.xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Nelstudio Blog</title>
    <updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Nelstudio Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://neldivad.github.io/img/n-mark-color.png</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to steal from the public without public attention]]></title>
        <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public</id>
        <link href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public"/>
        <updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today's generation is prosperous. But it's also plagued by problems similar to the past.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today's generation is prosperous. But it's also plagued by problems similar to the past.</p>
<p>Increasing wealth gaps, squeezed middle class, low birth rates, public debts that are increasing unsustainable, difficult job market.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2>
<p>The mainstream narrative now is that the rich have been exploiting the poor, and that all of the problems will go away if only we tax them enough or regulate their profits such that it is no longer predatory. Or, it's a specific race or cabal that is controlling the strings.</p>
<p>The problem with such reasoning is that the antagonist is too obvious. Too many people talk about them, and in fact most of the time people from the past fell for the same narrative. When revolutions end up happening, it wasn't clear if the rich was actually the problem.</p>
<p>In the French Revolution, it's not about the 99% against the 1% as we so commonly believed. It's more like the <a href="https://x.com/GaletteSaw6/status/1892255392987582924/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">top 1% against the top 0.1%</a>. Most of the common people don't even get represented while they get taken into the violent ride.</p>
<p>Put simply, associating wealth with crime is fallacious. The reason why this narrative gets momentum is because it appeals to the envious. I argue it's in the interest of people who are actually doing the stealing to misdirect public attention away from them to people with big numbers.</p>
<p>How then should one find the dishonest actor that explains all of the present problems and injustice without resorting to sloppy reasoning that matches what the mainstream wants you to antagonize?</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="discovering-the-anatomy-of-the-heist">Discovering the anatomy of the heist<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#discovering-the-anatomy-of-the-heist" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Discovering the anatomy of the heist" title="Direct link to Discovering the anatomy of the heist">​</a></h2>
<p>Most understand that problems and inefficiency don't come out of nowhere, therefore something/someone must be responsible. The next thing to be aware would be if the observed inefficiency is <strong>deliberate</strong> or <strong>accidental</strong>.</p>
<p>Many things that contribute to the growing wealth gap are participated by market players accidentally.</p>
<p>Example, the growth in job complexity and bureaucracy accidentally created wealth gap between those who have exposed themselves to enough cultural capital (through tertiary education) to perform bureaucratic tasks while leaving behind those who cannot afford <a href="https://wcer.wisc.edu/docs/working-papers/Working_Paper_No_2017_2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tertiary education to gain the cultural capital</a> required to stay compliant to current regulations and complexity demand.</p>
<p>If you look at things objectively, you may understand that dumb regulations and dumb degrees / license to bypass these regulations are the <strong>root of problem as to how some people unjustly got ahead / left behind</strong>. Yet, you hardly hear the mainstream complaining about this problem.</p>
<p>In fact, getting a degree, expecting stricter regulations, and going through very selective labor vetting process has become a cultural dogma that few even draw the connection that this is a possible vector for social division.</p>
<p>On a related topic, the other day I had an argument with my sister about the effectiveness of state education, the most extreme case being China's Gaokao -- The same system that is the <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/22125868211035802?icid=int.sj-abstract.citing-articles.192" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">most unfair and repressive to lower class</a> also happened to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/China/comments/17334c1/comment/k42ydza/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">get the most support and defense from the lower class</a>.</p>
<p>Gaokao creates "unequal" outcomes and "widening social class," in the sense that it forces the lower class youth to live and think that their life is a predictable grind (IE: another form of serfdom). But to many families, having a child that performs well in state exams is their only lotto to have their social status raised. Their defense to such a system is another example of people "accidentally" creating social division.</p>
<p>In effect, the gaokao system seems to be fall under the a category I would classify as "opportunity stealing hero" (OSH).</p>
<p>If you are convinced that China's gaokao creates net inequality (not through measurements of wealth, but through psychology where competitive students lose their independence of thought to conform to the grind culture), then you'll also find that most state's public education don't do better.</p>
<p><a href="https://educationdata.org/public-education-spending-statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In US, public schools spend $20k per student</a> for the results of <a href="https://www.thenationalliteracyinstitute.com/post/literacy-statistics-2024-2025-where-we-are-now" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20% illiteracy rate</a>. Acquiring information on YouTube, skillshare will not cost a curious individual more than $500/yr.</p>
<p>If the objective of public education is to increase public literacy and standardized knowledge to promote cultural equality, the results have been opposite -- education administrators are overpaid while young students get dumber and taxpayers get even more broke.</p>
<p>Yet, public educators continue to enjoy powerful political advantages, social returns, and positive public opinion. Another example of OSH.</p>
<p>With 3 examples, we can begin to find the anatomy of the heist by observing the commonalities.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Must have a way to avoid competition</strong>, either through political protection (state education) or high barriers to entry (creating more regulations, requiring higher ranking licenses), etc.</li>
<li><strong>Decisions are undemocratic</strong> (regulations setup by "think tanks" and "experts")</li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/China/comments/17334c1/whats_the_deal_with_chinas_gao_kao/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Victims having "Stockholm syndrome"</strong> to net negative practices</a>. (The hero convinces the victims who had been taken advantage that they in fact benefit from the transaction)</li>
</ul>
<p>With such leads, finding out who else fit such a bill is more productive than being told who is the antagonist.</p>
<p>If you enjoy where your logic will take you, stop scrolling and start thinking and see if your answers match with mine later.</p>
<p>I will do the honors and take the risk of exposing institutions with questionable motive and outcomes.</p>
<p>Here goes.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="heist-showdown">Heist Showdown<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#heist-showdown" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Heist Showdown" title="Direct link to Heist Showdown">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="central-banks">Central banks<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#central-banks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Central banks" title="Direct link to Central banks">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="uncompetitive">Uncompetitive<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#uncompetitive" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Uncompetitive" title="Direct link to Uncompetitive">​</a></h4>
<p>Central banks serve as the lender of last resort -- a function that allows them to provide emergency liquidity to banks, thereby forestalling systemic collapse.</p>
<p>But no one else gets this right to create value out of nothing. While it's hard to say they are dishonest, there is no way we can know how accountable too.</p>
<p>In a competitive market, an unaccountable bank would face consequences for poor policies. In central bank's case, mostly its just "bad luck", "bad timing", "oops".</p>
<p>For CB with weaker political power, it is possible for market players to force a competitive decision. (EG: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskEconomics/comments/altvbm/the_man_who_broke_the_bank_of_england/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">George Soros breaking the BoE by betting against their bad policies</a>)</p>
<p>For stronger CB, especially the US Federal Reserve,
<a href="https://www.econlib.org/yes-monetary-policy-did-cause-the-great-depression/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">it took decades for people to realize and agree some disastrous results done by central banks.</a></p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="undemocratic">Undemocratic<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#undemocratic" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Undemocratic" title="Direct link to Undemocratic">​</a></h4>
<p><a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/faqs/about_12591.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The public cannot elect a Fed Chair; the selection process is conducted behind closed doors with little transparency</a> -- comparable in its secrecy to the election of a pope.</p>
<p>The Fed Chair can make policies that influence credit markets such that it directly kills business or raise portfolio value.</p>
<p><a href="https://sites.lsa.umich.edu/mje/2023/09/04/why-the-2-inflation-target/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The 2% inflation target is a dogma, not an expert research or public agreement.</a> I can read the whole link to you. Or I can just tell you it's all vibes.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enough-victims-with-stockholm">Enough victims with Stockholm.<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#enough-victims-with-stockholm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enough victims with Stockholm." title="Direct link to Enough victims with Stockholm.">​</a></h4>
<p>Many are “victimized” by policies done by CB. If you own cash, the real value of their money is eroded by inflation.</p>
<p>Yet, most can't reject this poison, especially if you are an office workers with state contracts (where do you think the state gets their money to pay your contract work?), are a homeowners whose asset values grow together with each successive rounds of money printing.</p>
<p>If you work in office, your employment is likely an illusion. They will still raise back enough taxes from you to make back the money they printed to pay you <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-1-859c07" id="user-content-fnref-1-859c07" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup>. If you have any more left to spend, they will devalue it by printing the next round of money.</p>
<p>We become unwitting “Stockholmers” by growing psychologically dependent on a system that also steals from us.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="human-resources-and-recruiting-industry">Human resources and recruiting industry<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#human-resources-and-recruiting-industry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Human resources and recruiting industry" title="Direct link to Human resources and recruiting industry">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="anticompetitive">Anticompetitive<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#anticompetitive" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Anticompetitive" title="Direct link to Anticompetitive">​</a></h4>
<p>Have you met a department that is in charge of firing and hiring HR?</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="undemocratic-1">Undemocratic<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#undemocratic-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Undemocratic" title="Direct link to Undemocratic">​</a></h4>
<p>HR and recruitment comes up with lots of policies that have consequential effects to the market, yet they are not subjected to the agreement of their customers.</p>
<p>For example, HR policies routinely use expensive educational degrees as prerequisites for roles -- even when the actual performance gap between degree holders and non-degree holders is negligible in many real-world contexts.</p>
<p>In effect, HR legitimizes the value of expensive educational degrees simply by using it as a prerequisite to the roles they have. This isn't problematic if educational degrees do actually have value as a competency signal.</p>
<p>To find out if degrees, licenses, or other credentials are actually a competency signal, a scientific method would be to look at the data by systematically measuring the quality of both recruits and rejects using an objective function.</p>
<p>I have hardly met any HR that does this <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-2-859c07" id="user-content-fnref-2-859c07" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>It doesn't help that degree standards are getting lower while jobs are getting more complex. These days, the performance gap of degree owners and non-degree owners are negligible in the real world.</p>
<p>Degrees now function more like a "ticket you buy for the chance to work" that <a href="https://www.greeneuropeanjournal.eu/pierre-bourdieu-cultural-capital-in-the-21st-century/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gatekeeps labor supply to include only those who can afford a 4 year hiatus and 100k expense.</a></p>
<p>HR could easily fix their poor policy by simply letting themselves subjected to a scientific method, where they measure the quality of their recruits and the lack of quality of their rejects. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy">I've suggested a simple way to do it.</a></p>
<p>Yet, there is simply no market, competitive, moral pressure to do so.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="victims-with-stockholm">Victims with Stockholm<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#victims-with-stockholm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Victims with Stockholm" title="Direct link to Victims with Stockholm">​</a></h4>
<p>Business owners, shareholders, and job seekers think we are better off with them.</p>
<p>What people don't ask is how many of the problems the HR / recruitment industry solves are problems created by a bureacracy (that recruiters could be part of).</p>
<p>Example: employment rights, unions, protection of workers supposedly protect workers from unfair labor practices (Stockholm warning). But this also make it much harder for business owners to hire and fire employees, thus justifying the need for HR / recruiters.</p>
<p>The 2nd order effect is that business are less willing to hire and invest in employees, given that underperforming employees are so hard to let go.</p>
<p>I can't make the call that we are better off without labor regulations. But its important to understand the more complex we make labor laws, the more power HR and recruiters get. At some point, job seekers lose and business owners lose.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="is-it-a-middleman-problem">Is it a "middleman problem"?<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#is-it-a-middleman-problem" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Is it a &quot;middleman problem&quot;?" title="Direct link to Is it a &quot;middleman problem&quot;?">​</a></h2>
<p>I believe most of the bad things in life are not intentional. It's very rare to meet someone with a mission of causing as much damage as they can while getting away with it.</p>
<p>This means its important to inspect for systems that are supposedly "good" but at some point stop serving the interest of the system consumer.</p>
<p>What I notice is that problems that are so complicated to need a middleman tends to attract "careerist"<sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-3-859c07" id="user-content-fnref-3-859c07" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup> to setup uncompetitive bureaucracy (IE: rent-seeking toll).</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="but-arent-the-rich-the-real-final-boss">"But aren't the rich the real final boss?"<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#but-arent-the-rich-the-real-final-boss" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;But aren't the rich the real final boss?&quot;" title="Direct link to &quot;But aren't the rich the real final boss?&quot;">​</a></h3>
<p>It's too convenient, too big of the brush, and often results in bad policies. Instead, I think it's more helpful to expose people to the anatomy of how institutions can take advantage of the public.</p>
<p>So long as the public are uncritical about their practices, the bureacracy can keep masquerading as a value-creator when its a parasite <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-4-859c07" id="user-content-fnref-4-859c07" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup>.</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-859c07">
<p>Interestingly, <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/tax/10/history-taxes.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">federal income taxes we paid for granted started when the CB was invented at 1913</a>. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-1-859c07" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-859c07">
<p>I've spoke around recruiters during informal settings. In most of my conversations with recruiters, the best indicator of a good candidate is "what other recruiters" say about them. In logical settings, this is known as "circular reasoning". It's as unscientific as "just vibes". Yeah, you think people who make important decisions are more responsibile. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-2-859c07" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-859c07">
<p>Career usually mean something better than job and supposedly requires more respect. But rent-seeking can also be a career. The question is should the public sponsor such careers? <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-3-859c07" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4-859c07">
<p>Parasite is a strong word, but the classification is that it must grow infinitely at the expense of the host's strength. This is consistent with my observations. The Fed gets stronger everytime they print more money and do not hesitate to increase their personnel. Similarly, HR went from 0.5% workforce to 1.5% workforce from 1980 to 2020. In the same time with the growth of these institutions, their "customers" get weaker. This is unlike competitive economic systems (example Nvidia) where their growth is also followed by the growth in strength by their customers. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-4-859c07" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Len</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/neldivad</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="essays" term="essays"/>
        <category label="recruitment" term="recruitment"/>
        <category label="hiring" term="hiring"/>
        <category label="economics" term="economics"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The real function of taxes]]></title>
        <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes</id>
        <link href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes"/>
        <updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taxes are dumb.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Taxes are dumb.</p>
<p>It's hard to be controversial to say so. Most people who worked and earned money for a living would be frustrated by the whole experience that is so embedded in modern society, to the point it becomes something we learned to be helpless about.</p>
<p>This post won't try to change the way taxes work. I'm too small of a player for the legal system to give a damn about.</p>
<p>That said, I can explain how taxes work in a way that the common person will learn, and people can decide if taxes are worth it.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="modern-monetary-theory">Modern monetary theory<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#modern-monetary-theory" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Modern monetary theory" title="Direct link to Modern monetary theory">​</a></h2>
<p>Modern money is all fiat, meaning it is not backed by anything. Not gold, not oil, just blind trust. Actually, it is backed by the power of military<sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-1-b7afc1" id="user-content-fnref-1-b7afc1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup>, but we will leave the story to another day.</p>
<p>If we are to accept that money is not backed by anything, a state theoretically doesn't need to collect taxes before they spend -- they can just spend on what they want and pay it back later by raising taxes, or to do nothing and devalue all cash and savings.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-bother-collecting-taxes">"Why bother collecting taxes?"<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#why-bother-collecting-taxes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Why bother collecting taxes?&quot;" title="Direct link to &quot;Why bother collecting taxes?&quot;">​</a></h3>
<p>Great question. The amount of effort it takes to collect taxes is enormous.</p>
<p>Using the US as an example (its the most available one to build my priors) <a href="https://taxfoundation.org/data/all/federal/irs-tax-compliance-costs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the estimates of tax compliance cost of the $546 billion, or nearly 2 percent of GDP.</a></p>
<p>Annually, the US government raises <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/FYFRGDA188S" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17% of GDP as taxes</a>.</p>
<p>In effect, we are spending $25 for every $100 we harass a productive business to give the state.</p>
<p>This number includes taxes paid through active means (IRS audits) and passive means (taxes on income, VAT). If we are to estimate the cost of active collection and the actual tax revenue active collectors raised, it may be less than the cost it takes to finance active collectors.</p>
<p>It's like spending $100 on debt collectors (debt isn't even a right word as it implies we owe the state our production) to raise something less than $100.</p>
<p>If the objective of taxes is really to raise capital to afford projects, active collection seems ineffective at what they do.</p>
<p>Instead of answering why are we doing something inefficient, let's start with what happens if we just do nothing.</p>
<hr>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="case-1-really-doing-nothing">Case 1: Really doing nothing<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#case-1-really-doing-nothing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Case 1: Really doing nothing" title="Direct link to Case 1: Really doing nothing">​</a></h3>
<p>No government spending, no taxes, constant supply of money. The state is literally sleeping at the wheel.</p>
<p>Unrealistic scenario, but suppose this happens we should predict inflation to be 0%. This seems like a time when we have a perfect currency.</p>
<p>The problem is that the economy becomes perfectly competitive, which means those that earn will hold more currency and control a bigger share of the network (mercantilism).</p>
<p>The currency becomes less representative to those who are weaker or less competitive. With no state spending, there is no safety net except for private charities.</p>
<p>If people expect spending will cause them to lose power to sellers, then transactions are seen as zero-sum and the economy gets more illiquid.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="case-2-doing-anything-the-state-wants">Case 2: Doing anything the state wants<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#case-2-doing-anything-the-state-wants" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Case 2: Doing anything the state wants" title="Direct link to Case 2: Doing anything the state wants">​</a></h3>
<p>State prints as much money as it wants, gives out as much to anyone who will vote for them. Never collects any of them back.</p>
<p>Sounds too good to be true. Now people stop producing because there is no reason to. When there is no production, all the money can't buy anything -- you have a hyperinflation situation.</p>
<p>There's more! When people expect the currency to get weaker, the network of producers becomes more reluctant to accept the currency -- people rather do a barter trade or keep good things for themselves than to take your currency.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="case-3-spend-now-collect-back-everything-later">Case 3: Spend now, collect back everything later<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#case-3-spend-now-collect-back-everything-later" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Case 3: Spend now, collect back everything later" title="Direct link to Case 3: Spend now, collect back everything later">​</a></h3>
<p>The "perfect" scenario. The state spends as much as it wants to get something done, then get back all the money it spent back from people through taxes.</p>
<p>No net inflation, and stuff gets done! What's the problem?</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="there-is-always-a-better-deal">There is always a better deal<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#there-is-always-a-better-deal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to There is always a better deal" title="Direct link to There is always a better deal">​</a></h4>
<p>There is a more perfect scenario -- stuff gets done, and people keep all the newly minted currency. If something valuable was already done, why waste energy to give back the catalyst (ie: the currency)?</p>
<p>The problem happens when the currency gets spent on more things than it was made to spend on (IE: buying labor for social services becomes salary to spend and compete on limited goods) -- Taxes ensures the velocity of created money is not infinite.</p>
<p>In practice people can always argue why they don't need to return the currency, so its hard to take back as much money as we created.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whose-stuff-gets-done">Whose stuff gets done?<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#whose-stuff-gets-done" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whose stuff gets done?" title="Direct link to Whose stuff gets done?">​</a></h4>
<p>The state can create money to buy for things they want, but in practice you can bet the decisions aren't fair (IE: what the state wants to buy might not be what the people want to buy).</p>
<p>In fact, the state can just set up a shell company with their entourage, print some money and pay his friends and declaring his friends are being "paid to do social work". -- This is wastage in a nutshell.</p>
<p>In practice, things are not so blatant. Its more likely for state actors to set up lots of layers of agency that takes some cut of the budget, where the agency also happens to contain a share of the state's entourage -- also known as "deep state".</p>
<p>So a scenario with perfect balance sheet is not perfect if the work paid to do / things bought isn't representative.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="crowding-out">Crowding out<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#crowding-out" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Crowding out" title="Direct link to Crowding out">​</a></h4>
<p>If the state prints money to hire workers, then it means someone else would lose the worker they wanted to hire to do their work.</p>
<p>In a free market, the most important work gets done first and that is reflected by prices and bids.</p>
<p>When the state spends money, it is unclear if the work that needs to be done are the most important ones.</p>
<p>When suboptimal decisions are made and financed, in effect that is also a net loss to the people. It's like saying you win 10% doing something when you could have won 50% doing nothing -- a good outcome is not a valid defense for a good decision.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="its-all-decisions">It's all decisions<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#its-all-decisions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to It's all decisions" title="Direct link to It's all decisions">​</a></h2>
<p>Notice the theme here. The state can do anything it wants, but its decisions must be sound (IE: logical, benefits the people, within budget).</p>
<p>A sound decision is one that is profitable. IE: You spend little to do a lot.</p>
<p>When the state does something suboptimal, the net effect is the people's standard of living will devalue because they:</p>
<ol>
<li>need to ask more taxes from the people to pay back what they spent.</li>
<li>print more money to pay back what they spent, creating inflation.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>In modern finance, taxes are paid so inflation does not happen.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-not-just-let-inflation-happen">"Why not just let inflation happen?"<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#why-not-just-let-inflation-happen" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Why not just let inflation happen?&quot;" title="Direct link to &quot;Why not just let inflation happen?&quot;">​</a></h2>
<p>Great question. If the net effect of ineffective state spending is lower standards of living, and the way it is delivered can be either passive (through inflation) or active (through taxes), we could choose to do nothing.</p>
<p>Why go through all the hassle and trouble to feel pain?</p>
<p>I could write a whole post on how money works, how it flows. But the short answer I discovered after 20 years of studying money is: "it's all politics".</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You will never understand bureaucracies until you understand that for bureaucrats procedure is everything and outcomes are nothing. -- Thomas Sowell</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Actually... <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-2-b7afc1" id="user-content-fnref-2-b7afc1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-3-b7afc1" id="user-content-fnref-3-b7afc1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup></p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-b7afc1">
<p>Modern fiat currencies aren't entirely worthless. Typically currency is legitimized through public confidence. A currency that can be printed endlessly would mean more people opting out of the network. But confidence is fragile and fluctuates, so a mandate and force is more reliable. You will notice that reserve currencies tend to be controlled by contries with the strongest military. It is no coincidence. Having a gun means you accept whatever value there is on the paper. This is also a short story why I think cryptocurrencies are unviable. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-1-b7afc1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-b7afc1">
<p>Unlike inflation that erodes power indiscrimately, taxes are are more targeted to specific people. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-2-b7afc1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-b7afc1">
<p>There is a perspective where taxes make sense, like a "subscription" to the government. Some people uses more public services, like roads, hospital. So higher taxes are like your "silver, gold, platinum" subscription tiers. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-3-b7afc1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Len</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/neldivad</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="economics" term="economics"/>
        <category label="finance" term="finance"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[We can't afford job security]]></title>
        <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security</id>
        <link href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security"/>
        <updated>2025-01-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you understand government budgets, you will stop believing in job security.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you understand government budgets, you will stop believing in job security.</p>
<p>There is no such thing as job security -- especially not in a role without craftsmanship -- without taking away freedom from future generations.</p>
<p>Why? Because most people's idea of "job security" requires them to be a high paying white-collar bureaucrat in an office with a big corner desk.</p>
<p>Who wants to have a secure job that needs you to deal with dirt, danger, difficulties? If you can handle those 3Ds I guarantee your career is secure 100%. Incidentally, those are the jobs people look forward the most to be replaced.</p>
<p>Therefore, the reality is not that there is "no job security", rather it is "there is not enough non-3D secure jobs" in this world, because each one requires a government or bureaucracy to print or devalue existing currency to keep you and your desk.</p>
<p>When everyone thinks they are entitled to that illusion, what do you think is going to happen to future generations?</p>
<p>Some people worked hard to get a cushy, secure job as a C-level in some corporate, public office, conglomerate, consultancy, education institution.</p>
<p>An average person will think the price is decades of hard work climbing the career ladder and dealing with occasional office politics -- it is not the only price paid.</p>
<p>If the job is an administrative role where the "ascension" requires building a wall to keep off competitors (EG: adding regulations, raising licensing requirements to limit labor supply), paper pushing (office equivalent of digging a hole then filling a hole), it may be complicit in making some of the younger generations less free in doing productive work and less free with their social mobility.</p>
<p>If you ever felt "credential inflation" and lower conversion rates in job application rates, this is what's happening and you have the market that existed before you to thank.</p>
<p>If you are still young and starting out in your career, stop buying the idea or complaining about job security -- it was never there.</p>
<p>If it was, then the (money printing and deficit spending) ship has sailed and you need to start making something for yourself.</p>
<p>Look up your state's public spending, learn how to read financial statements of companies, and learn how money and value is created. You will quickly come to conclusion the only way wealth can be created is to do something that helps people and do it better (IE: getting better at your craft).</p>
<p>Most office jobs today are "state manufactured elites". IE: the state lends money for someone to get into college, get in debt, then offers them to be a slave for the state.</p>
<p>It is as ridiculous as minting your own crypto, selling "scholarships" to players by borrowing them your axoloties, and sending those axolotl to battle as a chore. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security#user-content-fn-1-6c131d" id="user-content-fnref-1-6c131d" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<p>The difference is one does it with fictional currency. The other does it with printed or taxed money.</p>
<p><a href="https://medium.datadriveninvestor.com/the-last-bullet-how-modern-finance-has-stole-enough-from-its-youth-2f2988b7b30a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">If you think its unsustainable, we are very close to the end of line.</a></p>
<p>If you want real job security, you must accept 3Ds, or be so good at your craft that no one beats you at your game.</p>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-6c131d">
<p>If you are wondering, it's Axie Infinity. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security#user-content-fnref-1-6c131d" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Len</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/neldivad</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="economics" term="economics"/>
        <category label="finance" term="finance"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to test your recruiting strategy]]></title>
        <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy</id>
        <link href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy"/>
        <updated>2025-01-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA["It's so hard to find talent." -- company]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"It's so hard to find talent." -- company</p>
<p>"The job market for SWE is cooked." -- Software engineers 2024</p>
<p>Logically, that can't be possible. But nothing in real life is perfectly logical. As engineers we need to diagnose and fix the problems.</p>
<p>In software, we have things like unit test, integrated test, system test.</p>
<p>As it complexity goes higher, we need live simulations, like hiring a game tester or setup Selenium to simulate a login process.</p>
<p>With the same philosophy, a company could hypothetically perform "recruiting test" that is really easy to do.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="recruiting-test-no-one-does">Recruiting test (no one does)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#recruiting-test-no-one-does" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Recruiting test (no one does)" title="Direct link to Recruiting test (no one does)">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-1-create-a-fictional-profile">Step 1: Create a fictional profile<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#step-1-create-a-fictional-profile" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 1: Create a fictional profile" title="Direct link to Step 1: Create a fictional profile">​</a></h3>
<p>with the ideal resume for the position you're trying to recruit.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-2-let-your-own-recruiter-call-back-your-resume">Step 2: Let your own recruiter call back your resume.<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#step-2-let-your-own-recruiter-call-back-your-resume" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 2: Let your own recruiter call back your resume." title="Direct link to Step 2: Let your own recruiter call back your resume.">​</a></h3>
<p>If it doesn't get past the phone screen, your recruiters are not doing their job.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proper-scientific-method">Proper scientific method<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#proper-scientific-method" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proper scientific method" title="Direct link to Proper scientific method">​</a></h3>
<p>If you have to do it scientifically, create 10 or 2-10% of applications with those profile. Do not announce to your recruiters you have this much "qualified simulated accounts" so the <a href="https://builtin.com/data-science/train-test-split" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">test set is not included in training</a>.</p>
<p>Check how much they missed as a benchmark, say 7/10 to measure you screening false negative rate.</p>
<p>You will solve the tech job shortage + tech unemployment.</p>
<hr>
<p>"It's going to waste 20 minutes of my life and phone call!"</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You waste months of life on a wrong hire. If your CEO picks up the phone just say congrats you done your work.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>"Creating and maintaining fictional profiles is so hard!"</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Everyone is using AI to generate their profiles already. They are also including as many frameworks (they are not even good at) as they can in resumes to hack the ATS keyword search.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Instead of investing on data science to figure out a better recruiting AI, use cheap data science to test your recruitment hit rate.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>"It makes a lot of sense but we don't want to do it"</p>
<p><a href="https://x.com/upstatefederlst/status/1872125343508971847" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">That's how we get tweets like this. </a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Len</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/neldivad</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="recruitment" term="recruitment"/>
        <category label="hiring" term="hiring"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Less is more]]></title>
        <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/less-is-more</id>
        <link href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/less-is-more"/>
        <updated>2024-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In any given business, the ideal state is that you can get away doing the least while creating the most outcome. In practice, idling looks like wasted cost, lost revenue. This philosophy is the result of us getting conditioned by centuries of economic model where labor time can be valued economically.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In any given business, the ideal state is that you can get away doing the least while creating the most outcome. In practice, idling looks like wasted cost, lost revenue. This philosophy is the result of us getting conditioned by centuries of economic model where labor time can be valued economically.</p>
<p>It is hard escaping being a victim to this hustling mentality, where simply believing that if one can put in more hours one would be achieving more -- this view get more wrong with every progress made to automation and technology.</p>
<hr>
<p>When I'm composing music, in any given moment not all instruments are busy playing their own notes, yet somehow they are still able to create an "effective symphony" with so little activity from each individual.</p>
<p>In fact, to achieve an effective symphony, it is necessary for pauses, emphasis, and passing spotlights to different parts and performers of the orchestra.</p>
<p>The best composers or conductors don't make everyone play all the time. When I was an amateur, I thought the requirement to be a good composer is complexity, difficulty, and novelty, yet I notice a lot of great composers can get away with composition that is simple to play (C-major), cliched progressions (4/4 time signature) (1-4-5-6 progression) and still hitting the top charts.</p>
<p>Inversely, a composition that is played by all parts of the orchestra constantly with complex maneuver are actually works done by an amateur. With the advent of digital music, it is now possible for composers to write in range and complexity that are impossible to perform.</p>
<hr>
<p>If difficulty and activity are signs of skill, then music topping the charts would have been electronic music with 10 instruments playing throughout the song at 200 BPM, with SFX automation clips stacked over one another. Clearly, the playlists we choose don't look like this.</p>
<p>Given the lack of correlation (that is continuing to decrease) between activity and outcome, somehow businesses and people who want to improve their personal career are still stuck with the mindset that "activity &gt;&gt; outcome".</p>
<p>Somehow, it is unacceptable for any employee to not have a backlog full of events. It is shameful to be seen by your friends that you don't have a full schedule one month ahead of you. You look like a loser if you don't have anything going on during your weekends or holidays.</p>
<p>Ask any artist, software developer, writer that is competent, and they always seem to arrive to the same answer-- effective emptiness, blanks, and space is required in a finished good product.</p>
<p>I think management and hustlers have a lot to learn from these people.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Len</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/neldivad</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="management" term="management"/>
        <category label="business" term="business"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anatomy of Ineffective leaders]]></title>
        <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders</id>
        <link href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders"/>
        <updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over 10 years of being someone's worker, leaders that own those characters demonstrate worse track records in company performance than leaders that don't have those characteristics.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over 10 years of being someone's worker, leaders that own those characters demonstrate worse track records in company performance than leaders that don't have those characteristics.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="speculating-on-stocks-or-futures">Speculating on stocks or futures<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#speculating-on-stocks-or-futures" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Speculating on stocks or futures" title="Direct link to Speculating on stocks or futures">​</a></h2>
<p>A leader should spend all their time creating and engineering a better future. Speculating on markets outside their expertise should be a waste of time if they really know what they are doing.</p>
<p>Even lower confidence if I peeked at their portfolio and notice them losing trades on speculative assets. Is that the reason why my boss urgently needs money and productivity?</p>
<p>There are some exceptions, where a great investor is also doing the hands-on work of running a company. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#user-content-fn-1-906ed7" id="user-content-fnref-1-906ed7" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="threatens-misbehaving-employees-with-pay-cut-and-termination">Threatens misbehaving employees with pay cut and termination<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#threatens-misbehaving-employees-with-pay-cut-and-termination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Threatens misbehaving employees with pay cut and termination" title="Direct link to Threatens misbehaving employees with pay cut and termination">​</a></h2>
<p>If an employee is a problem and you can do without them, terminate. Don't need to threaten.</p>
<p>If you must threaten, intimidation is a poor strategy to motivate someone who is underperforming or misbehaving -- a leader that makes a poor strategy is a poor leader.</p>
<p>What happens when you threaten is resentment and people preparing to jump ship as soon as they find the opportunity. Bad retention strategy.</p>
<p>Roll for persuasion, not intimidation.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="not-respectful-of-other-peoples-time">Not respectful of other people's time<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#not-respectful-of-other-peoples-time" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Not respectful of other people's time" title="Direct link to Not respectful of other people's time">​</a></h2>
<p>By showing up late, or keeping people overtime on projects or meetings.</p>
<p>Usually, this behavior is confounded with regular poor business judgment.</p>
<p>They tend to have budget issues and lack of manpower issues, but I hypothesize the true cause is that they cannot properly allocate priorities.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="underpays-or-too-much-cost-cutting">Underpays or too much cost-cutting<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#underpays-or-too-much-cost-cutting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Underpays or too much cost-cutting" title="Direct link to Underpays or too much cost-cutting">​</a></h2>
<p>You don't build a sports team that wins by buying players at wholesale prices. Lots of people do it, but I haven't seen one that works.</p>
<p>If someone really had a good solution to your problem, you pay as much as you can to get it.</p>
<p>Underpaying and cost-cutting is also a behavior that's confounded with priority issues similar to (3).</p>
<p>Underpaying, while it works against workers who are desperate enough to put up with those conditions, also has the effect of hiding the real costs of the problem.</p>
<p>Leaders will take for granted that this is all the investment that needs to get things done (at unsustainable prices) and think they have margins to pursue even worse market ideas.</p>
<p>You don't win from someone's losses by lowballing. You also lose out on real information that would have stopped you from pursuing bad ideas.</p>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-906ed7">
<p>In rare cases, I met leaders who are great investors and they are great people to work with as they understand macro, accounting, and good business models. I hold suspicion to leaders who are responsible for a large part of the company and its workers future, but somehow find time for short-term derivatives and engage with trading systems they cannot explain. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#user-content-fnref-1-906ed7" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Len</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/neldivad</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="management" term="management"/>
        <category label="business" term="business"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Blog Post]]></title>
        <id>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/first-blog-post</id>
        <link href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/first-blog-post"/>
        <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet...]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet...</p>
<p>...consectetur adipiscing elit. Pellentesque elementum dignissim ultricies. Fusce rhoncus ipsum tempor eros aliquam consequat. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>David Len</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/neldivad</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="bruh" term="bruh"/>
    </entry>
</feed>