<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rss.xsl"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Nelstudio Blog</title>
        <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Nelstudio Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We can't all get rich off compound interest]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This is a story I rarely share with anyone. But a lot of my problems are shared by other people and I wish more could come to understand the problems we have today.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a story I rarely share with anyone. But a lot of my problems are shared by other people and I wish more could come to understand the problems we have today.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="my-history">My history<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#my-history" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to My history" title="Direct link to My history">​</a></h2>
<p>Money has always been a problem for me since young. My parents are either dead or sick and I have to work a lot to support myself. It is also how I got the obsession in finance.</p>
<p>I majored in econometrics, thinking it will land me a job in finance. It didn't happen <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-1-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-1-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup>.</p>
<p>I ended up working for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@TickerSymbolYOU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a Youtuber</a>, built a quantitative trading research site that helped me understand markets and manage my own assets, built and sold multiple softwares for different companies.</p>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Details</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><p></p><summary>Preview of work I did in my quantitative research on micro</summary>
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://neldivad.github.io/assets/images/1-3d6530dd9c91bf86e9b43057244cef90.png" width="1450" height="752" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://neldivad.github.io/assets/images/2-f6ebbf943c8e18560616da3a0c4569a6.png" width="1843" height="847" class="img_ev3q"><p></p></div></div></details>
<details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Details</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><p></p><summary>Preview of work I did in my quantitative research on macro</summary>
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://neldivad.github.io/assets/images/3-cbba25dff532dbb6ccf1ec19c3d87289.jpg" width="994" height="684" class="img_ev3q">
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://neldivad.github.io/assets/images/4-fdc4aee9ca2aa50367940f6b69af2318.jpg" width="1520" height="1000" class="img_ev3q"><p></p></div></div></details>
<p>Nothing is easy, but doing the hard things exposes me to understanding the world better.</p>
<p>I want to do more, I respect others who can do more, and I want to help those who want to do. That said, it seems like things are getting more unfair for those who do <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-2-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-2-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup> and I need to start standing up for them.</p>
<p>I've attempted to explain some of those problems like <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public">bureacracy</a> and <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security">debt-financed opportunities</a> in some of my post. I think its unproductive to fight against other people and more productive to understand how the system we are working for sometimes fails to work for us.</p>
<p>I hope with my history and things I've worked on, I can convince you that I understand enough about money and macroeconomics to tell you what works and what doesn't, not just on an individual level, but also on a social level.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-illusion-of-financial-freedom">The illusion of financial freedom<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#the-illusion-of-financial-freedom" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The illusion of financial freedom" title="Direct link to The illusion of financial freedom">​</a></h2>
<p>For decades, financial independence has been touted as the golden ticket to a life free from the drudgery of soul-crushing jobs <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-3-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-3-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Financial independence can only be realized by the mechanism "compound interest" -- a force that makes your money grow exponentially. On paper, it's simple: you save enough money, invest in assets that yield returns, and watch your wealth snowball until you can finally retire.</p>
<p>It's as braindead as planting a seed that grows into a money tree, providing shade for you while you lounge all day.</p>
<p>Compound interest works by reinvesting your earnings so that future growth is based on both your initial capital and the accumulated returns. Financial influencers often paint a picture of an exponential curve. Advisors often tell people to start early and young and you will be 10x riicher than those who started 10 years later.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Compound interest is the 8th wonder of the world. He who understands it, earns it. He who doesn't pays it." - (Presumably) Albert Einstein.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There are many wrongs with this logic.</p>
<ol>
<li>This assumes that everyone can keep investing consistently for a lifetime.</li>
<li>This assumes that everyone will never run into any emergency situation or unexpected event that will force them to stop investing.</li>
<li>This assumes that your buying power in the future will be the same as your buying power in the past.</li>
<li>I've written an article with 100k views <a href="https://medium.com/datadriveninvestor/facts-about-financial-independence-no-one-talks-about-3835291539f3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">showing how it can't be done for everyone</a> (although now I explore more implication of the compound interest mechanism so its not a direct copy)</li>
</ol>
<p>Someone tried explaining the whole thing in 20 minutes that does fit a lot with what I know. The rest of the article will have similar takeaways of the video, more detailed explanation of the compound interest mechanism, as well as my anecdotal experiences with working class and investor class.</p>
<div style="width:100%;height:360px"></div>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="compound-interest-they-dont-tell-you">Compound interest (they don't tell you)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#compound-interest-they-dont-tell-you" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Compound interest (they don't tell you)" title="Direct link to Compound interest (they don't tell you)">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="lifecycle-conundrum">Lifecycle conundrum<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#lifecycle-conundrum" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Lifecycle conundrum" title="Direct link to Lifecycle conundrum">​</a></h3>
<p>Most people have only a limited window during which they can work, save, and invest. Students spend years building skills while incurring expenses, and retirees often face high living costs without any income. This means that the full power of compounding is never truly realized on an individual level.</p>
<p>For an average person <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-4-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-4-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup>, you start saving at 30, get compounding work for you from 30-60, and pray that your compounded value can support you post-60 plus your children's pre-30.</p>
<p>For compound interest to really work like the guru's story, you have to born rich, be a trustfund baby, spend as little expense on assets <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-5-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-5-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">5</a></sup>. Then, you start compounding as soon as you get access to a bank account at 18 and compound all the way to retirement.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-does-compound-interest-even-get-paid">How does compound interest even get paid?<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#how-does-compound-interest-even-get-paid" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How does compound interest even get paid?" title="Direct link to How does compound interest even get paid?">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="active-compound-interest">Active compound interest<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#active-compound-interest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Active compound interest" title="Direct link to Active compound interest">​</a></h4>
<p>Compound interest is not a scam.</p>
<p>In economics, maybe you start with an empty land.</p>
<p>First, you dig trenches. The "compound interest" is that its easier for you to fill up water and build a farm later. With a farm, the "compound interest" is the increased population in your land. With more population, the "compound interest" is more work getting done.</p>
<p>In a software example, you write a package. The "compound interest" is that package gets used in multiple microservices. With multiple microservices, the "compound interest" is apps with more functionalities. With more apps, the "compound interest" is more data was created. Data is the "compound interest" machine learning models. ML models is the "compound interest" of faster software development.</p>
<p>These are "active compound interests" in the sense that it's "paid" to you by letting you working on the next thing the new door has opened.</p>
<p>But what most of us are interested in is "passive compound interest".</p>
<p>How are you going to pay for that?</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="passive-compound-interest">Passive compound interest<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#passive-compound-interest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Passive compound interest" title="Direct link to Passive compound interest">​</a></h4>
<p>The same way its going to be paid like an active compound interest. You invest in "shovels" that let people "pick gold". Then, people give back some gold to you so you can buy more shovels to rent to other people.</p>
<p>There are a few problems:</p>
<ol>
<li>You will run out of people who want to pick gold.</li>
<li>Not everyone can be the guy owning shovels!</li>
</ol>
<p>When you invest in a company, its profits (aka your returns) stem from the efforts of countless employees. If everyone were to retire early, who would do the work to keep the pie baking?</p>
<p>This imbalance reveals a critical flaw: the dream of universal financial freedom and infinite compound interest is built on an unsustainable model.</p>
<p>When asset returns depend on the continuous labor of a relatively smaller group, widespread early retirement becomes a pipe dream. The returns compound because someone is still working hard, not because the system is magically self-sustaining.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="when-passive-compound-interest-is-too-much">When passive compound interest is too much<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#when-passive-compound-interest-is-too-much" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to When passive compound interest is too much" title="Direct link to When passive compound interest is too much">​</a></h2>
<p>Hopefully you understood the difference between active compound interest and passive compound interest, and I've shown you that there is a limit to passive compound interest -- the exponential growth of compound interest either does not happen, or the workers using your asset must be exponentially productive.</p>
<p>In both cases, this did not happen in real life.</p>
<p>Real economy did not grow as fast as asset price -- IE: workers did not get productive faster than the returns of asset owners.</p>
<p>What happens when the growth of shovel owners rents increases faster than the rate of gold picked?</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="passive-compound-interest-eventually-captures-ownership-from-the-worker">Passive compound interest eventually captures ownership from the worker<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#passive-compound-interest-eventually-captures-ownership-from-the-worker" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Passive compound interest eventually captures ownership from the worker" title="Direct link to Passive compound interest eventually captures ownership from the worker">​</a></h3>
<p>Many people really got rich doing nothing but owning. It's not necessarily a bad thing as they do assume risks of owning <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-6-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-6-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">6</a></sup> (which we may argue if its actually active compounding and not passive compounding).</p>
<p>However, the problem is now the ROI for asset owners outpaces the ROI of the worker (real GDP growth).</p>
<p>This has at least 3 consequences:</p>
<ol>
<li>Workers have less purchasing power to be a consumer in alternative investments / economies.</li>
<li>More workers quit picking gold and move on to owning shovels.</li>
<li>Workers that can't own shovels will work harder to get ahead, essentially getting squeezed out of the market in the long term.</li>
</ol>
<p>From the video shared above, what the author realized is that his ventures that depended on the consumers buying power (restaurants) didn't turn out as well as simply owning assets like gold, stocks, or property.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you allow the rich to grow and grow, once you hit your natural limits, the rich will continue to grow by basically cannibalising the existing middle class.
And that's not because they're evil. It's simply because their wealth is so large and grows so quickly and there are so few actual real investment opportunities that basically they have no other option.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="anecdotes">Anecdotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#anecdotes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Anecdotes" title="Direct link to Anecdotes">​</a></h2>
<p>In hindsight, many active choices had been worse than passive choices.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: The past is not a prediction of the future. What worked before will not continue working in the future. Do not use these anecdotes to decide your future. It is here to show you problems of the economy for the last few decades that led to the profitability / unprofitability of some decisions.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dropshipping-and-adsense">Dropshipping and Adsense<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#dropshipping-and-adsense" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dropshipping and Adsense" title="Direct link to Dropshipping and Adsense">​</a></h3>
<p>In 2001-2010, I remembered the gold rush in the internet economy of dropshipping and creating and blog and financing it with Adsense.</p>
<p>As a teen with money problems and desperation, these are the labor I subscribed heavily into. I spent money on courses, domains, built my own projects, tried selling, made a lot of mistakes.</p>
<p>It's not unprofitable, so naturally it starts inviting a lot of competitors that dilutes the returns.</p>
<p>With hindsight, engaging in the gold rush might not be the best move. I should have just bought the stocks of AMZN and GOOG and the risk-adjusted ROI is much higher than competing heavily in dropshipping and Adsense.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="games-and-coin-mining">Games and coin mining<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#games-and-coin-mining" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Games and coin mining" title="Direct link to Games and coin mining">​</a></h3>
<p>Game development is challenging. Its more hardware demanding than other industries, so you have many developers trying to optimize code to fit in the hardware requirements.</p>
<p>Bitcoin mining also had the same problem, and it turns out there exist a company that specialized in solving these niche computing requirements -- Nvidia.</p>
<p>Again, in hindsight the average game developer and bitcoin miner should quit early and buy Nvidia stock.</p>
<p>This is a guy who tried starting his own company that ended up failing and got into a situation where many would not expect someone of his position to be.</p>
<div style="width:100%;height:360px"></div>
<p>From Robert:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It's easy to give advice about what to do if you could go back into the world of 10 years ago, but your life is not going to start 10 years in the past and the conditions of the world today are completely different. If I was able to rewind the clock and go back to working at Amazon or Nvidia directly after graduation I could have been a millionaire by now $20,000 worth of Nidia stock options from 2014 would be worth about $5 million today.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>But then again most of the money would have come from the appreciation of the company stock not from the salary of actually working there. So the best strategy would have been to just get a student loan and spend all of it on Nvidia stock and then go sit on the beach for the 5 years that I spent in school and the 10 years that I spent trying to start a business.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Incidentally, I happen to know a speculative guy in college who did just that and is doing way better than every person I know from my cohort.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="college-and-work">College and work<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#college-and-work" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to College and work" title="Direct link to College and work">​</a></h3>
<p>Speaking of college, I find myself agreeing to Robert. In my experience, my time and money in university has not justified its ROI -- I would been 10x wealthier today had I just invested all of my tuition fees into SP500 and used those 4 years working for minimum wage.</p>
<p>Likewise, trying hard to get my first job in my country also did not justify the ROI. The income I make (RM3000 as fresh graduate) <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-7-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-7-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">7</a></sup> barely covers the cost of living, travel, and food I need to work.</p>
<p>Even my own experience shows that an average startup / business often yields lower returns than simply investing in the stocks of established companies like those of their vendors like Cloudflare, Adobe, Amazon, Avid.</p>
<p>Again, past returns are not future expected returns. Do not use this information to make decisions for yourself.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-social-trade-off-of-financial-freedom">The social trade-off of financial freedom<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#the-social-trade-off-of-financial-freedom" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The social trade-off of financial freedom" title="Direct link to The social trade-off of financial freedom">​</a></h2>
<p>At its core, the promise of compound interest -- and by extension, early retirement -- is a double-edged sword. The system only works if the working class continues to toil, fueling the growth and profits that asset owners enjoy.</p>
<p>If everyone were to chase financial independence by retiring early, there is no labor to sustain the economic engine. If you want workers, but you also want compound interest, it means you have to squeeze the working class out of ownership and opportunity.</p>
<p>When working class is squeezed, you will see consumption markets to underperform the general market -- restaurants, videogames, music, movies, content, etc. are unprofitable because no one has any money to spend -- it is going to come and bite back the owner's interest.</p>
<p>Printing money and paying people money to work in a bureaucracy is also not sustainable <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-8-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-8-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">8</a></sup> -- all you're doing is increasing the cost of living, delaying the pain, while also decaying your population to do stupid stuff over more productive things (like starting families) during their most productive years until they become old, useless, and poor.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="real-compound-interest-is-active-compound-interest">Real compound interest is active compound interest<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#real-compound-interest-is-active-compound-interest" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Real compound interest is active compound interest" title="Direct link to Real compound interest is active compound interest">​</a></h2>
<p>True financial independence isn't about chasing an ever-expanding line on a graph. It's about living within your means and acknowledging the limits of our economic system.</p>
<p>While early retirement is possible for some, it often comes at the cost of increased social inequality. The pursuit of "passive income" is a seductive myth -- each "passive dollar" comes from someone else's hard work.</p>
<p><strong>The real compound interest is the doors you or other people's asset has opened to you.</strong> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-9-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-9-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">9</a></sup></p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Compound interest is the 8th wonder of the world. He who understands it, earns it. He who doesn't pays it." - Albert Einstein.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>With AI, a working class get to make use of so many people's data, algorithms and create things millionaires from 10 years ago couldn't.</p>
<p>That said, the owner class needs more critical examination. At some point, passive compound interest becomes unfair and social cohesion will decay. It is also in the owner's interest <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fn-10-ac6b4a" id="user-content-fnref-10-ac6b4a" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">10</a></sup> to ensure that the working class is not squeezed out of the economy so that they can continue to work and create value.</p>
<p>If its really hard to agree on how much compound interest owners should get, maybe the simpler way to grow is to just get rid of bureaucrats. Seriously, why do you need people stopping other people from working?</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-ac6b4a">
<p>COVID happened, suddenly there is a hiring freeze and I lost all contacts that could land me a role in banking. I had to rebuild my life from scratch and that got me to code and write music. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-1-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-ac6b4a">
<p>Nothing is fair and people often advised that I should be taking advantage of those signals instead of exposing them to really make change. I don't care about ROI. I just think its important for people who want to understand to hear what I have to share. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-2-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-ac6b4a">
<p>That I seriously don't believe it needs to be done. Many "soul-crushing" jobs have no reason to be there, other than it being a product of "debt-financed opportunities". Basically the CB prints money to employ people doing BS jobs, basically a form of "UBI" with extra steps. All the money you gain, you lose it to rising cost of living (because people who actually made products to lower CoL had been stolen to work for the bureacracy), to taxes, to inflation, to having less time to do other things. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-3-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4-ac6b4a">
<p>It's not even average. That's also assuming you don't do stupid stuff like getting into drugs, credit card debts. Or suffer from shocks like layoffs, health emergency, family death, divorces, unlucky childbirth, etc. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-4-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-5-ac6b4a">
<p>Like living in your parent's house, borrowing someone's car, borrow everything you can from other people. There is no shame. You are just getting the most out of compound interest. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-5-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 5" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-6-ac6b4a">
<p>Most homeowners make less than you think. They make money by renting more than their installment payments. But houses needs repairs and its not uncommon for a single repair to set back the owner by few years worth of rental income. This also discounts the risk of vacancy, unlawful tenant, fires, theft, vandalism. Sure, they build equity while doing so. If the cost of owning is less than what they would have spent on rent, or if it is less than the price appreciation, they are "winning" the market. What happens when house prices decreases (like most of non-owners wish to happen)? <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-6-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 6" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-7-ac6b4a">
<p>Malaysian wage offers are pathetic. After adjusting for tuition fees and national wages, Malaysia ends up as <a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2015/10/the-11-most-expensive-countries-for-a-university-degree/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">top 5 most expensive country for university education</a>. So much talent (including me) refusing to work locally for this reason. I think the lowball offers are consequence of the bureaucracy and commercial culture -- hard to apply for a job, hard to hire someone with all the paperworks, hard to raise money because every investor just buys real estate (Malaysia tax and laws doesn't benefit equity as much as real estate). I don't want to deal with any of this and I just work with anyone who DMs me on Discord. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-7-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 7" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-8-ac6b4a">
<p>I'll argue that the lack of sound money, a centralized currency that can be manipulated and artificially push people into pointless labor is the source of all problems. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-8-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 8" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-9-ac6b4a">
<p>Or the doors your asset has opened for other people. To be sustainable, the toll should not be higher than the gains other people get from using your asset. Else, they will just quit working and start bidding for your asset until one of you is out of cash and devolve to serfdom. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-9-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 9" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-10-ac6b4a">
<p>Anyone who owns SP500, has retirement savings, has a house is an owner. It's not just the top 1% that is the owner. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-all-get-rich-off-compound-interest#user-content-fnref-10-ac6b4a" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 10" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>essays</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When not to negotiate]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Some battles can't be won.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some battles can't be won.</p>
<p>Not everyone can be negotiated with and giving the wrong person what they want can be a a pathway to ruin.</p>
<p>That said, my intention for writing this article is not to encourage pessimism for my readers. On contrary, I want to show that 99.9% of the time, a mutually positive transaction is possible because most disagreements we have are a result of things we imagine we will lose.</p>
<p>Even in cases where the opponent tries to take advantage of the transaction, it benefits them to know that they are better off splitting the difference with you than to walk away without a deal.</p>
<p>However, I will not encourage naivety and tell the comforting lie that "everything is negotiable with the right approach and clever tactics".</p>
<p>Some people enter negotiations with no intention of finding balance. They want everything and will use your willingness to compromise as a weapon against you.</p>
<p>This isn't pessimism; it's a crucial distinction that will save you time, resources, and emotional energy. Recognizing when negotiation is futile is strategic wisdom.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="understanding-objectives">Understanding objectives<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#understanding-objectives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Understanding objectives" title="Direct link to Understanding objectives">​</a></h2>
<p>In <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_strategy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">grand strategy</a>, the most common optimization it aims to achieve is to maximize a country's long-term national interests.</p>
<p>There is no written solution to the problem of national interests or how a country should play, but so far we have reduced them to 2 categories:</p>
<ul>
<li>limited objectives: an opponent that leaves you alone after getting what they want (material, status, security)</li>
<li>unlimited objectives: an opponent whose primary objective also includes your destruction, on top with any material, status, security they can get out of you</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unlimited-objectives">Unlimited Objectives<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#unlimited-objectives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Unlimited Objectives" title="Direct link to Unlimited Objectives">​</a></h2>
<p>Have you tried to reach an agreement with someone who kept moving the goalposts, and with each concession you made, they'd introduce new demands?</p>
<p>While these people may not want the destruction of you, what they are doing is close to what someone with UO will behave.</p>
<p>People with unlimited objectives don't want a fair deal -- they want to extract maximum value while giving nothing in return. Every advantage you concede doesn't bring you closer to resolution; it widens the power gap between you.</p>
<p>Think of it like feeding a stray cat. The first time might seem like a one-off kindness. But tomorrow? They'll be back, expecting more, getting aggressive if you don't deliver. That's the UO pattern.</p>
<p>What makes negotiation impossible is that UO people view compromise as weakness. Your willingness to meet halfway signals an opportunity for exploitation, not collaboration.</p>
<p>It is also a form of enablement that encourages more parasitic behaviors. Your concession not only hurts youself, but also the opponent, as well as other 3rd parties trying to live honestly.</p>
<p>Here are some examples of entities that systematically have characteristics of UO.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="state-government-bureaucracies">State, government, bureaucracies<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#state-government-bureaucracies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to State, government, bureaucracies" title="Direct link to State, government, bureaucracies">​</a></h3>
<p>Bureaucracies are an emergent form of community at large scale -- where every agent tries to optimize for their own interests and relative social status.</p>
<p>While these organizations are made by people, they are similar to a market where no single agent can influence its course of action. By design, they cannot appeal to morality or individuality.</p>
<p>As a result, most bureaucracies are optimized to grow as much as they can while maximizing the relative power gap between the institution and an independent agent.</p>
<p>Look into history and observe how often bureaucracies grow in personnel size and how infrequent they shed the size of their followers, managers, or employees?</p>
<p>The outcome of every bureaucracy has been the same: they keep growing until they can no longer finance themselves. Then, a debt collapse happens (which usually leads to large scale civil war or external invasion).</p>
<p>Every tax you pay, every paperwork you put up with, every time you waste on their rituals makes the bureaucracy more legitimized, more powerful, and harder to get rid of.</p>
<p>I've witnessed this pattern in smaller settings like corporates, local community clubs, even within online communities.</p>
<p>A Discord server initially allowed users to voice concerns at meetings. When participation grew, they changed rules to limit speaking time, then moved meetings to inconvenient times, then required pre-approval for topics. Each concession from users led to further restrictions, not progress. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fn-1-859932" id="user-content-fnref-1-859932" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="cancel-culture">Cancel culture<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#cancel-culture" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cancel culture" title="Direct link to Cancel culture">​</a></h3>
<p>Public apologies rarely satisfy online mobs.</p>
<p>While a lot of people who got into online drama do so for bad reasons, complaining and mudslinging as a netizen is not a civic way of solving problems.</p>
<p>If you ever tried to think independently and suggest different solutions that conflict with the online mob's idea of justice, you will often find yourself being very unpopular.</p>
<p>Like a bureaucracy, an online mob is no longer an individual that owns the ability to negotiate. Rather it has a new found purpose to consume and destroy as much as possible to justify and grow its existence.</p>
<p>When someone apologizes for a perceived transgression, the admission doesn't resolve the situation -- it accelerates it. The objective isn't correction or growth; it is punishment and social control.</p>
<p>The most prominent examples I have observed are conservative voices in social media before 2024 (peaked in 2020), where accounts get banned for conservative content, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google%27s_Ideological_Echo_Chamber" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">employments and contracts getting rescinded for conservative participation</a>, <a href="https://www.refinery29.com/en-us/2019/07/237347/h-m-racist-hoodie-controversy-diversity-problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">businesses getting cancelled for accidental perception of racist expressions</a>, and so on.</p>
<p>This contrasts sharply with traditional reconciliation models. Christian forgiveness (at its best) creates a path back to community for those who had sinned. Forgiveness serves a crucial social function -- it prevents eternal outcasts and exiles. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fn-2-859932" id="user-content-fnref-2-859932" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup></p>
<p>When someone's objective is your permanent exclusion rather than your improvement, negotiation becomes impossible.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unremorseful-criminals">Unremorseful criminals<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#unremorseful-criminals" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Unremorseful criminals" title="Direct link to Unremorseful criminals">​</a></h3>
<p>There is a reason we incarcerate violent offenders -- someone who has demonstrated willingness to harm others for personal gain has crossed a fundamental social boundary.</p>
<p>When lenient sentences repeatedly land on unremorseful offenders, we're not showing mercy -- we are enabling escalation and endangering the law-abiding public. This is why capital punishments have been topic of debate that never seems to be resolved.</p>
<p>As civil people, we don't like punishing people severely, but we also have to admit certain severe punishments need to be in place to deter crime. It is hard to balance between optimal leniency or toughness because often the generated results are mixed and cannot guarantee a good policy.</p>
<p>In terms of our private judgement, it makes a lot of sense to keep people demonstrating patterns of predatory behavior to incur more severe punishments for each repeated offense.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="monopolies">Monopolies<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#monopolies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Monopolies" title="Direct link to Monopolies">​</a></h3>
<p>The best way to negotiate with a profit maximizing firm with no competition is to create competition.</p>
<p>I haven't seen a monopoly that improves their product after raising prices. Every additional margin of profit given from the consumer to the monopoly creates a worse experience and product for the consumer.</p>
<p>Examples of monopolies I've witnessed in Malaysia are <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Road_Transport_Department_Malaysia" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JPJ</a> (driving license issuer). The product never improves, the instructors always have an attitude, and it was always a hassle to get or renew a license. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fn-3-859932" id="user-content-fnref-3-859932" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="limited-objectives">Limited Objectives<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#limited-objectives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Limited Objectives" title="Direct link to Limited Objectives">​</a></h2>
<p>People with limited objectives actually want resolution.</p>
<p>When someone has specific, reasonable goals, negotiation works because reaching those goals ends the conflict. They don't view each concession as an invitation to demand more but rather as a progress towards conclusion.</p>
<p>That said, most of the conflict we have today are due to either of us <strong>mistaking our opponent to have UO when they actually only have LO</strong>.</p>
<p>If you notice the examples I have given for UO, it is more likely that it belongs to an institution or crowd. On a personal level, very very rarely will you find someone that operates with UO.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="family-romantic-partner">Family, romantic partner<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#family-romantic-partner" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Family, romantic partner" title="Direct link to Family, romantic partner">​</a></h3>
<p>I have a friend who often argues with his partner in relationship. Both are competitive at winning the argument, despite the arguments being very mundane (someone forgot the housework, someone accidentally locked another person out).</p>
<p>Despite the arguments being very straightforward in LO (EG: just finish the housework and move on, just unlock the door and move on), rarely do arguments get settled like that. A lot more ego and grudge was invested into those arguments.</p>
<p>When I asked both if they thought their relative status in the relationship would diminish if they conceded the arguments and admitting mistakes, both agreed.</p>
<p>When I asked if they will take advantage of their partner's mistake and raise their status after the event, they hesitated but ultimately decided cooperation is more important than power.</p>
<p>In summary, <strong>both have the idea that their partner has UO over them, therefore they can't afford to lose a single argument</strong> or it would be harder for them to defend themselves in the next argument.</p>
<p>I also see this happening between father and son, where the father refuses to let his son win any argument regardless of how reasonable the son is because losing power is bad for the father when it comes to correcting future misbehavior.</p>
<p>When they both understood each other's true fear (partner has UO) and discovered the solution (both have LO), both sides finally opened up -- <strong>the mistaken will concede the argument with an agreement that their partner will not use that opportunity to diminish respect and status of the mistaken.</strong></p>
<p>In a relationship with love, this agreement is a no brainer -- of course we want our partners to correct their mistakes without losing anything.</p>
<p>It ended up as a very productive agreement, not only in terms of the outcome but also to the quality of the relationship going forward.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="workplace">Workplace<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#workplace" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Workplace" title="Direct link to Workplace">​</a></h3>
<p>When you work in sales, your real job is to identify what they actually want. People often say what they want, but not their underlying objective. This is the main reason why many business transactions don't close.</p>
<p>I have a friend who had a hard time selling his product to a client as the management is very resistant to the product. Through conversation, I discovered the management's real concern wasn't the solution, rather the fear of being redundant during implementation. When addressed, the opposition vanished. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fn-4-859932" id="user-content-fnref-4-859932" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="signs-of-unlimited-objectives">Signs of unlimited objectives<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#signs-of-unlimited-objectives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Signs of unlimited objectives" title="Direct link to Signs of unlimited objectives">​</a></h2>
<p>That said, don't be naive and don't be destructively compassionate. You have to look out for 0.1% of people who are willing to be ruthlessly destructive and are often manipulative.</p>
<p>Before entering any negotiation, ask yourself: Does this person want something specific, or do they simply want more? Are they seeking resolution, or do they thrive on conflict itself?</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="moving-goalposts">Moving goalposts<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#moving-goalposts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Moving goalposts" title="Direct link to Moving goalposts">​</a></h3>
<p>When each concession triggers new demands rather than bringing closure. Its time to cut the losses and move on.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="history-of-scorched-earth-conflicts">History of scorched-earth conflicts<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#history-of-scorched-earth-conflicts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to History of scorched-earth conflicts" title="Direct link to History of scorched-earth conflicts">​</a></h3>
<p>When someone leaves devastation in previous disputes, it looks like a parasite that has done killing its host, and is finding a new one to put up with them.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pleasure-in-your-distress">Pleasure in your distress<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#pleasure-in-your-distress" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Pleasure in your distress" title="Direct link to Pleasure in your distress">​</a></h3>
<p>When someone seems more energized by your suffering rather than by resolution its best not to owe them any favors. For some of you unlucky people, you might know a few friends like that. You cannot take a single thing from them as that debt cascades into an UO over you.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="most-people-have-limited-objectives">Most people have limited objectives<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#most-people-have-limited-objectives" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Most people have limited objectives" title="Direct link to Most people have limited objectives">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>A lot of times, people who express signals above don't do it intentionally</strong>. When you point out that they are operating with UO, it is very likely they will immediately adjust their behavior if they really cared about the cooperation.</p>
<p>99.9% of people aren't out there to destroy you. They're simply advancing their interests within normal social boundaries.</p>
<p>Your neighbor wants quiet after 10 PM, not your constant misery. Your employee wants fair compensation, not your company's bankruptcy. Your customer wants a working product, not your financial ruin. Your partner wants sex, conversation, and respect, not all of your assets and dignity.</p>
<p>Understanding this distinction prevents paranoia and enables productive engagement with the majority of people you'll encounter.</p>
<p>Too many times we mistaken our opponent to have UO when they actually only have LO. Even if some expressed behaviors of having UO, many times it is due to emotional reasons they don't even notice themselves doing it. If you show them that they will get more using the LO approach, they will eventually recognize what's good for them and adapt their interest.</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-859932">
<p>Rules are inevitable when network starts scaling. But I observe communities that get transformed the quickest into bureaucracies is when <strong>there is social status to be gained by moderators</strong>. Status become zero-sum and moderators are encouraged to set up a bureaucracy to maintain their relative status to wall off young blood and new competitors, even at the expense of the absolute power of the community. For any startup founder, <strong>you are the only link</strong> between the difference of a community with leader and a bureaucracy -- the culture starts and dies with you. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fnref-1-859932" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-859932">
<p>A culture that churns out exiles will be unstable in the long run. When people are left behind or are "irredeemable", not only can't they positively contribute to the community, they will actively raise the severity of their crimes and create more long-term losses for a culture (might as well go big or go home). Forgiveness is necessary, but blind forgiveness is enabling. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fnref-2-859932" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-859932">
<p>You can call it a state bureaucracy. I was being generous with the definition and decided to call it a monopoly. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fnref-3-859932" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4-859932">
<p>It's an AI product. It's hard selling software until managers are comfortable that the product will not be a threat to their jobs. For the same reason, you observe companies spend irrationally on McKinsey interns for projects with little business outcomes. The real thing they are paying for is to avoid getting fired by their shareholders for bad policy. Management consultants have already mastered this market of "Status-as-a-service". <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/04/when-not-to-negotiate#user-content-fnref-4-859932" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>essays</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Illusion of productivity]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In today's fast-paced, hyper-connected world, the pressure to be productive is irrationally relentless.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today's fast-paced, hyper-connected world, the pressure to be productive is irrationally relentless.</p>
<p>We are constantly reminded that productivity is the key to success -- that subsequently has been corrupted to believe that productivity is essential for survival and preservation.</p>
<p>Many of us feel an overwhelming urge to engage in activities that we perceive as productive -- be it through social shame, keeping up with society, to avoid political conflict through GDP growth.</p>
<p>However, this desire and engagement for productivity cannot be fulfilled because there is a hidden consumer that is destroying a lot of wealth, leading to a lot of frustration for those trying to get ahead.</p>
<p>The article intends to challenge the conventional wisdom that equates busyness with productivity and explore how many supposedly productive activities are, in fact, forms of consumption.</p>
<p>We will examine several examples, including the consumption of information, education, compliance, opportunities, and financial liquidity, to illustrate this point and encourage a reevaluation of what it truly means to be productive.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="consumption-of-information">Consumption of information<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#consumption-of-information" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Consumption of information" title="Direct link to Consumption of information">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="news-and-market-research">News and market research<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#news-and-market-research" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to News and market research" title="Direct link to News and market research">​</a></h3>
<p>This is counterintuitive for most people to understand, especially when many were raised before the digital age where they still believed that studying and learning is productive.</p>
<p>But one of the most pervasive forms of consumption masquerading as production today is the consumption of information.</p>
<p>In the digital age, access to vast amounts of information has never been easier. We subscribe to newsletters, follow thought leaders, and engage in market research, often under the pretense of staying informed and making better decisions.</p>
<p>However, literacy is no longer a problem today, rather its the distractions that is caused by generated noises.</p>
<p>The reality is that much of the information we consume today does not translate into tangible productive outcomes. Instead, it often serves as a form of cultural capital, providing a sense of being "in the know" without yielding real value.</p>
<p>How many of our LinkedIn doomscrolls translate into tangible career outcomes?</p>
<p>How many of the news on Twitter written by "shiptalkers" ends up helping us make better crafts?</p>
<p>How many equity research we read on SeekingAlpha, Substacks, and Medium translate into tangible trading signals?</p>
<p>The world is full of informed people that can't produce great crafts. We have too many people falling for the <a href="https://fs.blog/green-lumber-fallacy/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">green-lumber fallacy</a>.</p>
<p>This is not to say that information is not valuable, but when it becomes an end in itself rather than a means to an end, it is consumption.</p>
<p>As a rule of thumb, if what you read ends up making "someone else richer" instead of "you getting richer", it is consumption.</p>
<p>The time spent consuming information could often be better spent on actual productive activity, such as doing hobbies, building relationships, friendships -- outcomes that typically emerge from "consumption leisure time".</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="consumption-of-credentials">Consumption of credentials<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#consumption-of-credentials" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Consumption of credentials" title="Direct link to Consumption of credentials">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="tertiary-education">Tertiary education<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#tertiary-education" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Tertiary education" title="Direct link to Tertiary education">​</a></h3>
<p>Another area where consumption masquerades as production is in the realm of tertiary education.</p>
<p>Education is often seen as a productive pursuit, as it equips individuals with skills and knowledge that can enhance their productivity. This is mostly true only for STEM fields.</p>
<p>Even then many STEM jobs can still be taught to any curious mind and not exclusively reserved for those with expensive degrees.</p>
<p>But as many people would have observed when attending colleges, the motivations behind pursuing higher education are not always altruistic or productive. In many cases, the drive to acquire degrees and certifications is driven by credentialism -- the demand for certified skills.</p>
<p>Credentialism is a form of consumption, as it mandates a BS requirement that results in misaligned priority -- where the destructive motivation to acquire credentials hijacks the productive motivation to acquire useful skills or knowledge.</p>
<p>Individuals who pursue education solely for the sake of credentials are not producing -- <strong>they are submitting to an irrational demand for certification.</strong></p>
<p>This phenomenon not only distorts the purpose of education but also creates a mismatch between the skills individuals possess and the skills the market truly needs.</p>
<p>We are also discounting the problem where going to college "crowds-out" a person from participating 4 years of productive labor and being exposed to the competitiveness of market.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="coaching-and-online-courses">Coaching and online courses<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#coaching-and-online-courses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Coaching and online courses" title="Direct link to Coaching and online courses">​</a></h3>
<p>Similar philosophy applies.</p>
<p>If what you are learning is not solving your problem, or if the problem it is solving is <strong>less than the problem of your lack of credentials</strong>, it is consumption.</p>
<p>There is nothing wrong with learning more stuff and acquiring more cultural capital. But do not be fooled into thinking that is "productive".</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="consumption-of-compliance-and-ego">Consumption of compliance and ego<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#consumption-of-compliance-and-ego" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Consumption of compliance and ego" title="Direct link to Consumption of compliance and ego">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="management-and-bureaucracy">Management and bureaucracy<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#management-and-bureaucracy" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Management and bureaucracy" title="Direct link to Management and bureaucracy">​</a></h3>
<p>In a rational workplace, workers are hired to produce -- whether it's manufacturing goods, delivering services, creating research or content.</p>
<p>From my observation as well as many people's testimony, in many organizations the primary focus of work is less about production but rather compliance.</p>
<p><strong>Many employees are hired not to do work, but to make someone else feel more powerful.</strong></p>
<p>On the first glance it is not that straightforward, as no one will admit this is the case. But looking at the quantitative results, earnings, and profitability, it immediately exposes the true motivations of some people. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-10-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-10-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<p>Employees are expected to adhere to management structures, follow protocols, meet regulatory requirements. The most obvious examples being showing up to office 9-to-6, attending unnecessary meetings, requiring medical certification for absenteeism, and so on.</p>
<p>I understand for many businesses, compliance is a necessary evil to preserve discipline and decorum. A business or team that lacks discipline is a slippery slope that quickly cascades to failure. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-1-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-1-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-2-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-2-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup></p>
<p>While the origins of most protocols are well-intentioned, often they become bureaucratic exercises that consume time and resources without necessarily leading to more production -- more workers are hired ("productive") because more time of veterans has been spent on compliance ("consumption").</p>
<p>The economist's question is: "Before implementing any protocols, is all of the demand of compliance worth the cost?"</p>
<p>For most bureaucracies, they are not financially constrained to contemplate if hiring for compliances counts as wastage, especially if the institution is financed through public investment and public debt.</p>
<p>Many of them justify spending those cash on hiring people for compliances for a subset to feel more in control, often at the expense of shareholder's returns on equity or future taxpayers. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-3-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-3-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-4-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-4-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">5</a></sup></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="artistic-perfectionism">Artistic perfectionism<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#artistic-perfectionism" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Artistic perfectionism" title="Direct link to Artistic perfectionism">​</a></h3>
<p>Art, in its essence, is an act of creation -- a process that brings ideas to life and provides value to both the creator and the audience.</p>
<p>However, perfectionism is an act of consumption masquerade as productivity, as it hinders the creation of value by postponing work, and often benefits no one except to feed the irrational ego of the artist.</p>
<p>It is difficult to draw a line between a productive desire (having high standards and to avoid redundant work later) and a consumption desire (to postpone shipping quality work to satisfy ego) since they both come from similar drive of "wanting to achieve more".</p>
<p>It is important to recognize when this drive becomes excessive -- where there is an endless cycle of refinement, spending over budget to tweak details that are imperceptible to others.</p>
<p>At the heart of artistic perfectionism is often the fear of not being good enough. This fear can manifest as an intense need for control and perfection, driving the artist to overwork their craft.</p>
<p>While a certain level of ambition is healthy, when it becomes an obsession, any more "production" is quickly "consumed" by the ego -- no amount of productivity gains will result in growth if its all destroyed by the ego.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="consumption-of-opportunities">Consumption of opportunities<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#consumption-of-opportunities" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Consumption of opportunities" title="Direct link to Consumption of opportunities">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="non-merit-based-advancement">Non-merit-based advancement<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#non-merit-based-advancement" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Non-merit-based advancement" title="Direct link to Non-merit-based advancement">​</a></h3>
<p>The concept of opportunities is another area where consumption masquerades as production.</p>
<p>Entrepreneurship and deregulation has a positive externality to the market that is unrecognized and undervalued in the sense that it creates opportunity for other people to create value.</p>
<p>However, when opportunities are provided based on factors other than merit and wise risk-taking activity <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-5-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-5-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">6</a></sup>, they can become a form of consumption rather than production.</p>
<p>Consider hiring quotas, DEI, and other forms of "opportunity supply" that appeals to identity (although anything that is non-merit-based would result in destructive outcomes).</p>
<p>A naive person would think that these are a form of production, as they provide opportunities to people who would otherwise not get it under normal competitive scenarios. However, this deception can only fool those who cannot understand 2nd-order effects from such policies.</p>
<p>For anyone who understands 2nd-order effects, <strong>every non-merit-based opportunity supplied consumes the opportunity that would have otherwise been given to a more competitive person.</strong></p>
<p>To measure the outcome of "who is the net consumer of opportunities", we can look at the "net opportunity created" by a non-merit person relative to a merit person.</p>
<p>One might argue that an incompetent hire creates "more opportunities" as the problems and drama that come out of them means there is a demand for more people to come in and solve, whereas a competent hire does too much with too little, resulting in "creative destruction". Under "net employment" metrics this will be true.</p>
<p>However, a person that creates drama for other people to cleanup means other people have less time for other productive pursuits. A person that does "creative destruction" means other people are liberated from monotonous tasks to pursue more challenging tasks. Numbers cannot decide who is a net producer or consumer of opportunities, but qualitatively we all can decide which one is more preferable.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Got it, lets do merit-based by looking at resumes and credentials!"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If credentials are a signal to competence, then I'm sure many people wouldn't have any disagreements. That said, from our <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#consumption-of-credentials">previous session</a> and from this <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#human-resources-and-recruiting-industry">article</a>, I have expressed low confidence to those signals as they had suffered from <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/w/goodhart-s-law" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Goodhart's Law</a> and perverse incentives by the recruiting industry.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="esg-investments">ESG investments<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#esg-investments" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to ESG investments" title="Direct link to ESG investments">​</a></h3>
<p>If financial market is a form of resource allocation, then it constitutes a distributor of opportunities.</p>
<p>Under basic rules of financial markets, the most worthy business to obtain capital should be the one that creates the greatest shareholder return, IE: the highest ROI, ROC, ROE, or ROA. The rationale being that the generated value will be returned to shareholders as dividends, and investors will use those dividends to pursue more productive market opportunities.</p>
<p>However, due to the considerations of positive and negative externalities (eg: dirty mining companies, labor exploitative companies taking too much public capital), ESG investments are created to redirect capital to businesses with expectation that those business generate enough positive externaties to lift the rest of the market.</p>
<p>That said, we have given ESG investments enough time and the results haven't been promising. From valuation and profitability standpoint, many companies from ESG portfolios underperformed the general market (less profitable, higher price/earnings, lower yields).</p>
<p>Even the label "ESG" is not a reliable signal to measure the quality of a company pursuing socially beneficial goals. XOM -- an oil and gas company has a better CDP score than TSLA -- an electric car and robotics company.</p>
<p>The classification of what constitutes an ESG company is opaque, undemocratic, and seems to correlated with financial spending on ESG consultants and compliance.</p>
<p>Many companies that try to get an ESG certification do so not for the benefit of consumers, or even for the benefit of shareholders <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-6-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-6-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">7</a></sup>. Rather, its to conform to the "consumption of credentials" highlighted earlier.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="consumption-of-liquidity">Consumption of liquidity<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#consumption-of-liquidity" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Consumption of liquidity" title="Direct link to Consumption of liquidity">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="trading-and-financial-speculation">Trading and financial speculation<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#trading-and-financial-speculation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Trading and financial speculation" title="Direct link to Trading and financial speculation">​</a></h3>
<p>In the financial world, trading often feels like a productive activity because it involves doing "productive information acquisition" and making decisions. However, much of the trading that occurs in financial markets is actually a form of consumption.</p>
<p>Retail investors and traders frequently buy and sell assets without a clear rationale, often driven by emotions, speculation, or simply the desire to participate in the market.</p>
<p>If these activities do not yield better returns on a market-risk-adjusted basis, arguably they are simply consuming liquidity.</p>
<p>Financial advisors often warn against frequent trading for this reason, yet many trading platforms and market makers encourage it, as they have a vested interest in selling liquidity.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="trading-labor-patents-companies">Trading labor, patents, companies<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#trading-labor-patents-companies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Trading labor, patents, companies" title="Direct link to Trading labor, patents, companies">​</a></h3>
<p>On a more micro level, we can apply the same principles to labor markets, patents, and companies.</p>
<p>An employee that frequently looks for new jobs, changes jobs -- can be considered a productive activity if they are actively discovering information that helps their career progression that subsequently returns more value downstream from their new role.</p>
<p>However, the act of scouting also crowds out the productive activity of working hard and staying committed to the company. In effect, the relentless scouting consumes liquidity from the labor market by flooding recruiters with more data points to compete for a limited role.</p>
<p>Likewise, the same effect can be observed by recruiters who are constantly looking for new hires instead of creating incentives for existing employees to stay or be promoted.</p>
<p>A labor market with high turnover means lots of transaction costs involved, not to mention the cost of retraining new hires and the loss of productive momentum.</p>
<p>When you observe the market having a trend of greater spending in recruitment, shallow thinkers will mistakenly believe that the labor market is growing and subsequently a signal of a more productive economy.</p>
<p>Those who contemplate will realize it is the result of <strong>more liquidity consumers as a response</strong> to an increasingly inefficient market <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fn-7-df5ce1" id="user-content-fnref-7-df5ce1" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">8</a></sup>.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dating-and-romantic-relationships">Dating and romantic relationships<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#dating-and-romantic-relationships" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dating and romantic relationships" title="Direct link to Dating and romantic relationships">​</a></h3>
<p>Having higher expectations from prospective partners raises the bar for the quality of the relationship.</p>
<p>More people trying to meet this demand can be considered "productive" if they end up raising their own value in earnings, reputation, and social capital for their partners.</p>
<p>In practice, this is not what we observe. The explosion of choices means people are less commited, more choices, and subsequently more "liquidity consumers".</p>
<p>When people are busy spending time and money impressing the irrational public for the chance of companionship, it crowds out the productive activity of building a relationship that would have otherwise happened between two committed couples.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="anatomy-of-production-and-consumption">Anatomy of production and consumption<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#anatomy-of-production-and-consumption" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Anatomy of production and consumption" title="Direct link to Anatomy of production and consumption">​</a></h2>
<p>While I have given a lot of examples of net consumption activities masquerading as production, we can reduce the concept to a simple factor.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>If it has a dumb requirement, it is probably a consumption.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>No amount of increased productivity will satisfy a dumb requirement, and the result will still be a stagnation of progress.</strong></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="image" src="https://neldivad.github.io/assets/images/musk-engineering-a99ace623c04d6c112ca3afc907aebdc.png" width="721" height="354" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>In effect, doing the wrong thing is no better than not producing anything.</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-10-df5ce1">
<p>Pardon the sensitive example. It's like Hitler saying he is there to "win the war", but careful inspection will see that he is distracted by many campaigns of ethnic cleansing -- an irrationality not shared by leaders who are actually trying to win the war. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-10-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-df5ce1">
<p>Despite me practicing WFH most of my time, I would prefer not to if I can work with driven and competent people as the best creative work results from physical proximity. More importantly, juniors don't get left behind and actually stand a chance to learn and be promoted. WFH is very destructive for social mobility and I only anecdotally see it working for the privileged and driven, which I am very fortunate to be part of. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-1-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-df5ce1">
<p>I expect pushback from WFH advocates after all I said about dumb requirements. For work that is critical, physical proximity is essential. Most work are not critical, so WFH is still a net positive relative to showing up on office to satisfy a manager's desire for control. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-2-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-df5ce1">
<p>Some bureaucracy's consumption for compliance has grown so serious to the point it has directly caused the collapse of birthrates, as many people are forced to be employed in BS roles and crowded out the time they could have spent on raising families. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-3-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4-df5ce1">
<p>Basic intuition will refute that its the lack of money that is the core issue of declining birthrates. If the whole population is employed to upkeep a BS consumption (bureaucratic compliance), then all the salaries paid will still not afford a basic life as the cost of living will rise as fast as salaries getting paid. The net effect is shifting all the population's time from growing families to pushing papers in an office. We observe this happening in SK and JP, where employees make a lot of money by global standards but are not able to afford a basic life. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-4-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 5" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-5-df5ce1">
<p>A "wise" risk-taking action is when there is an asymmetrical upside relative to downside and does not outsource risk to the public. "Opportunities" financed by public-debt is not "wise" because it offloads downsides to the public. It is more correct to describe those debt-financed "opportunities" to be a consumption goods bought by "future taxpayers" -- depending on the outcome of those programs -- a positive ROI (scholarship) or a net value destruction (hiring  mascots to meet quotas). <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-5-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 6" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-6-df5ce1">
<p>If ESG really does benefit shareholders, the company would be more profitable, result in better valuation or growth after the certification. Instead, many of the returns generated post-certification are "circular" (IE: more capital raised from ESG funds that result in more expensive valuation but not profitability), or the "profitability" are revenue derived from government subsidy programs that taxes future public. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-6-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 7" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-7-df5ce1">
<p>The inefficient labor market can be caused by numerous reasons. Having dumb requirements and credentialism is one explanation. Having a high turnover rate is another. I'll be generous and think it has more to do with jobs getting more complex. When jobs are complex, it raises the transaction friction, which means the act of consuming liquidity is more costly. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/2025/03/01/illusion-of-productivity#user-content-fnref-7-df5ce1" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 8" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>essays</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Natural language is software]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When writing software, the longer we spend our lvies doing it, the more we often encounter tradeoffs in information, like abstraction and locality of behavior (LoB).]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When writing software, the longer we spend our lvies doing it, the more we often encounter tradeoffs in information, like abstraction and locality of behavior (LoB).</p>
<p>The core principle of abstraction is "Do not repeat yourself (DRY)". Meaning, we should avoid duplicating code and import whenever you need to.</p>
<p>The tradeoff is that behaviors get inherited too often, to the point where making any local changes become inflexible.</p>
<p>The most common example will be Bootstrap CSS. It tries hard to not repeat itself, so you have class components all stuffed within a <code>style.css</code> file.</p>
<p>The issue happens when you want to change the look of a component. You have to go through the entire file and find the class you want to change. Often you realize there is a lot of collisions of CSS between different class names, EG: <code>.table-striped</code>, <code>.table-striped-primary</code>, <code>table-dark-primary</code>, inheriting from <code>.table</code>.</p>
<p>At some point you forget which one does what, which one inherits which CSS, and you end up with a mess.</p>
<p>Tailwind CSS solves this by describing all the styles within the same file. EG: <code>class="bg-blue-500 text-white outline-none transtion-all duration-100 pd-1"</code>.</p>
<p>The problem with Tailwind CSS is that it is repetivive, so your code is very unreadable. When you work on both Bootstrap and Tailwind, inevitably you find that both suck for different reasons -- there is an inherent tradeoff between abstraction and locality of behavior.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="how-this-relate-to-natural-language">How this relate to natural language?<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#how-this-relate-to-natural-language" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to How this relate to natural language?" title="Direct link to How this relate to natural language?">​</a></h2>
<p>If you really paid attention, you notice that a lot of natural language we use take for granted of these principles.</p>
<p>You see "abstration", "LoB", and "collisions" happening all the time.</p>
<p>I will share the 3 language I'm most familiar with, being English, Japanese, and Chinese and show how each natural language overcome its encoding challenges, and how many of their problems can predict the problems of software projects that do share common traits with those natural languages.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="from-functional-to-object-oriented">From functional to object-oriented<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#from-functional-to-object-oriented" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to From functional to object-oriented" title="Direct link to From functional to object-oriented">​</a></h2>
<p>In software development, the transition from functional programming (FP) to object-oriented programming (OOP) is an evolution to manage complexity.</p>
<p>FP emphasizes pure functions, meaning functions do not modify variables but instead generate new ones as an output. Pure functions are "pure" because they always return the same output for the same argument values. In effect, it serves as a very simple motif for any program.</p>
<p>OOP focuses on encapsulation, inheritance, and polymorphism, so state changes are supported and behavior can be extended.</p>
<p>The natural language equivalent of FP is the use of alphabets (English), <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_character_strokes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">character strokes</a> (Chinese), hiragana (Japanese) to convey meaning.</p>
<p>However, users of the natural language will eventually realize that using only basic building blocks result in lots of redundancy. Also, if the sequence of characters repeats too often, it also gets confusing to interpret.</p>
<p>A programmer that deals with a functional programming framework will also come to feel the same problem after working on the project long enough (redudancy, confusion during long sequences.)</p>
<p>The natural language equivalent of OOP is the use of prefixes, suffixes, and roots to convey meaning.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="linear-extensions-in-object-en">Linear extensions in object (EN)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#linear-extensions-in-object-en" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Linear extensions in object (EN)" title="Direct link to Linear extensions in object (EN)">​</a></h2>
<p>In English, words are often built from smaller parts, almost like how LEGO pieces fit together to make something bigger. Take the word "carbon monoxide" as an example. Each part of the word means something specific:</p>
<ul>
<li>Carbon: a type of element</li>
<li>Mono: meaning "one"</li>
<li>Oxide: a type of compound derived from oxygen element</li>
</ul>
<p>When you put these pieces together, they form a new word that tells you it's a compound made of one carbon atom. Even if you're not a chemistry expert, the word gives you clues about what it means!</p>
<p>This modular approach is cool because it lets us understand and create new words by combining familiar parts. It's like how you can mix different LEGO pieces to build something entirely new.</p>
<p>However, the linearity and locality of English means you will often get very long words when trying to describe something specific or technical.</p>
<p><code>Pneumonoultramicroscopicsilicovolcanoconiosis</code>, which has 45 letters, refers to a lung disease caused by inhaling silica dust.</p>
<p>How it came to be this long is because you want to fit and extend multiple classes into an expression <code>pneumo</code>, <code>micro</code>, <code>silica</code>, <code>osis</code>, and you required the locality, IE: fixing all the motifs together so those classes don't get accidentally spilled to a different word.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="component-attachment-in-object-cn">Component attachment in object (CN)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#component-attachment-in-object-cn" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Component attachment in object (CN)" title="Direct link to Component attachment in object (CN)">​</a></h2>
<p>In Chinese, many characters are built from smaller parts called radicals or components, which give clues about their meaning. This is similar to object-oriented programming in software, where objects can include other objects or inherit their properties.</p>
<p>Most of the oldest and common characters are pictographs (象形; xiàngxíng), representational pictures of physical objects.</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>日 (rì) means "sun"</li>
<li>月 (yuè) means "moon"</li>
<li>木 (mù) means "tree"</li>
</ul>
<p>Just like how you mix LEGO pieces, Chinese combines these common words to become themes of other words, known as 部首 (bùshǒu).</p>
<ul>
<li>明 (míng) is made by combining 日 (sun) and 月 (moon). Together, they mean something bright.</li>
<li>晨 (chén) means "dawn" and uses 日 (sun) to show light.</li>
<li>果 (guǒ) means "fruit" and uses 木 (tree), showing where fruit comes from.</li>
</ul>
<p>Unlike English where expression get extended by adding suffixes and elongating the word, Chinese extend expression by fitting multiple "components" (IE: the primary characters) into a box and identifying it as a unique character. You can treat each Chinese character as an individual script file.</p>
<p>This compression means Chinese has a natural advantage to use very little words to convey lots of meaning.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="example-1">Example 1:<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#example-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Example 1:" title="Direct link to Example 1:">​</a></h4>
<blockquote>
<p>掌声的嗜好成了瘾症</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The preference for applause has become an addiction.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="example-2">Example 2:<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#example-2" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Example 2:" title="Direct link to Example 2:">​</a></h4>
<blockquote>
<p>在深海漩涡里翻腾摧毁一切只剩下无可挽回的罪人</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The waves of the whirlpool in a deep sea are breaking everything, leaving behind only a guilty person with no redemption.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In effect, Chinese has demonstrated the advantage of a more compressed abstraction, most obviously the number of phonemes required to finish a sentence.</p>
<p>However, anyone who has done enough software will soon guess the next problem with Chinese component approach.</p>
<p>Chinese has a lot of characters. In effect, each character is a class of its own, therefore your database of words requires a huge collection.</p>
<p>Unlike English where you only need 26 characters (maybe more if you also want to include Greek symbols or accented symbols), Chinese has between <a href="https://www.hutong-school.com/how-many-chinese-characters-are-there" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">3000 to 100,000 characters</a> (depending on the level of complexity of the dictionary) you are using.</p>
<p>Not only that Chinese has more characters to track because each expression "wants" a word to represent it, we either have to create a new word to represent the expression, or we have to borrow a reserved word to represent it (IE: similar but have different meanings). This is the software equivalent of "class collision".</p>
<p>While one can always squash more components into the script, the obvious disadvantage is that the character becomes harder to write and unnecessarily niche. Check out the abomination of the few examples that still survived today:</p>
<ul>
<li>攀 (Pān) (Climbing)</li>
<li>罐 (Guàn) (Can)</li>
</ul>
<p>One obvious solution is to use compounded words to represent the expression.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="塑料-sùliào-plastic">塑料 (sùliào) (plastic)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#%E5%A1%91%E6%96%99-s%C3%B9li%C3%A0o-plastic" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 塑料 (sùliào) (plastic)" title="Direct link to 塑料 (sùliào) (plastic)">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>塑: shape</li>
<li>料: material</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="细菌-xìjūn-bacteria">细菌 (xìjūn) (bacteria)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#%E7%BB%86%E8%8F%8C-x%C3%ACj%C5%ABn-bacteria" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 细菌 (xìjūn) (bacteria)" title="Direct link to 细菌 (xìjūn) (bacteria)">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>细: fine</li>
<li>菌: fungus</li>
</ul>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="方言-fāngyán-dialect">方言 (fāngyán) (dialect)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#%E6%96%B9%E8%A8%80-f%C4%81ngy%C3%A1n-dialect" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to 方言 (fāngyán) (dialect)" title="Direct link to 方言 (fāngyán) (dialect)">​</a></h4>
<ul>
<li>方: square, direction</li>
<li>言: speech</li>
</ul>
<p>You notice this compounding style is very similar to English method of linearly extending a word with suffix: EG: "hydrophobic" as "water-repelling".</p>
<p>However, the problem with Chinese that the characters they can extend is restricted by all the options they can use from the 3000-word dictionary in the first place. 3000 characters isn't enough to cover every concept relative to English where you can use any word as  suffixes, prefixes, and roots.</p>
<p>This abstraction makes Chinese very "opinionated" in terms of how concepts can be extended, much like our experience as developers with OOP languages.</p>
<p>You can observe this disadvantage very obviously during EN and CN attempts to describe a technical or scientific concept (CN is much more ambiguous than EN).</p>
<ul>
<li>Penicillium chrysogenum</li>
<li>产黄青霉菌</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="inventing-new-object-to-be-attached-to-old-object-jp">Inventing new object to be attached to old object (JP)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#inventing-new-object-to-be-attached-to-old-object-jp" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Inventing new object to be attached to old object (JP)" title="Direct link to Inventing new object to be attached to old object (JP)">​</a></h2>
<p>In Japanese, much of the ancient scripts are based on kanji characters, which uses the same writing system as Chinese but with different meaning.</p>
<p>In the meantime around 8th century, the Japanese had the demand to represent the sounds of the spoken language more accurately. They invented a "manyogana" system, where Chinese characters were used to represent phonetic sounds rather than their original meanings. Its the equivalent of repurposing a class with different functions (bad, bad, bad idea in software).</p>
<p>Eventually, sounds and phonemes became a mainstream way of encoding language. To avoid the confusion of shared class problem, the Japanese adopted 2 new writing systems: hiragana and katakana to represent sounds.</p>
<p>Hiragana, a syllabary with a limited set of characters, serves a functional purpose by providing phonetic values. But independently it runs into the problem of FP -- expressing a complete sentence is lengthy, confusing, and hard to read.</p>
<p>To make things more readable, the Japanese combined hiragana with kanji. The result is a writing system using 2 distinct character dictionaries.</p>
<p>From a software developer's perspective, this is a maintenance nightmare. It's like adding a plugin (hiragana) to your monolith (kanji). Not only do the user needs to understand each character from kanji, now they also need to understand each character from hiragana.</p>
<p>But this combination also solves some big problems, like "class collision" and limited ways to expand experienced by CN. It's like giving LEGO pieces different colors.</p>
<p>For example, the kanji 生 (せい, しょう) can mean "life" or "raw," and when combined with different hiragana, it forms different words.</p>
<ul>
<li>生まれる(うまれる) (生-mameru): to be born</li>
<li>生み出す(うみだす) (生-midasu) : to create, to invent</li>
<li>生きる (いきる) (生-kiru) : to live</li>
</ul>
<p>This is just a tip of the iceberg for Japanese interaction between kanji component and hiragana component. More advanced use of langage include compounded kanji that result in different pronounciation.</p>
<p>Example kanji 月 (つき / tsuki), which means "moon" independently. When combined compounded with different kanji results in different hiragana pronounces.</p>
<ul>
<li>月刊 (げっかん / gekkan): means "monthly," like a magazine you get every month.</li>
<li>一月 (いちがつ / ichigatsu): means "January,"</li>
<li>満月 (まんげつ / mangetsu): means "full moon"</li>
</ul>
<p>The base <code>tsuki</code> can have its state changed to <code>gek-</code>, <code>gatsu</code>, <code>getsu</code> depending on context.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-lot-of-software-is-history">A lot of software is history<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/natural-language-is-software#a-lot-of-software-is-history" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A lot of software is history" title="Direct link to A lot of software is history">​</a></h2>
<p>The evolution from functional to object-oriented structures in language is a challenge every developer have to go through as they raise in seniority.</p>
<p>Writing code and maintaining software seriously will also expose developers to the tradeoffs of abstraction and locality of behavior.</p>
<p>Software developers must manage libraries, frameworks, dependency hell, exponential explosion of required context (aka tech debt).</p>
<p>Alternatively, you can pay attention to how natural language spent thousands of years evolving to solve the same problem. Often, natural language give us a clue on the architecture of software, as well as predicting in advance the problems those designs will eventually face.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>essays</category>
            <category>software</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is conformism a viable survival strategy?]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We celebrate heroes, entrepreneurs, artists, and independent thinkers. These individuals are often showcased as beacons of innovation and progress.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We celebrate heroes, entrepreneurs, artists, and independent thinkers. These individuals are often showcased as beacons of innovation and progress.</p>
<p>Yet, despite this glorification, conformism remains is the norm, not exception through all observed history.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="the-paradox">The paradox<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#the-paradox" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to The paradox" title="Direct link to The paradox">​</a></h2>
<p>At any given moment, the majority tends to follow established norms, whether they are being conservative or simply unable to form independent thoughts.</p>
<p>If we value independence and innovation so highly, why do conformists continue to outnumber independent thinkers?</p>
<p>Is there an inherent advantage to conformism that ensures its prevalence, or are we merely paying lip service to the idea of valuing independence?</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="evolutionary-perspectives-on-conformism-and-defiance">Evolutionary perspectives on conformism and defiance<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#evolutionary-perspectives-on-conformism-and-defiance" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Evolutionary perspectives on conformism and defiance" title="Direct link to Evolutionary perspectives on conformism and defiance">​</a></h2>
<p>From an evolutionary standpoint, traits that confer a survival advantage are more likely to persist and propagate.</p>
<p>If independent thinking provided a clear evolutionary edge, you should expect independent thinkers to gradually outpace conformists.</p>
<p>However, historical observation contradicts this expectation. Conformists have consistently outnumbered independent thinkers across different eras.</p>
<p>This begs the question:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Does independent thinking hold an evolutionary disadvantage?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Does conformism offer unseen benefits that contribute to group survival and cohesion?</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="deep-diving-conformism">Deep diving conformism<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#deep-diving-conformism" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Deep diving conformism" title="Direct link to Deep diving conformism">​</a></h2>
<p>It is easy to have low opinions about conformism, or towards conformists. Yet, most of us don't recognize how much conformism we do on a regularly basis.</p>
<p>It makes a lot of sense to follow the crowd. In data science, there is a K-Nearest Neighbors algorithm that is used very often and efficient to compute, especially if the application needs to make the prediction fast.</p>
<p>An example of a KNN is to associate a Japanese user with the average Japanese user. The software doesn't try to do fancy computation to model the user at high fidelity.</p>
<p>In financial markets, there is a trend following strategy, or ARIMA models, where the prediction of prices is based on past few day's prices. It's more "braindead" relative to exhaustively analyzing earnings report, growth rates, transcripts to predict prices and to generate a new valuation every time data changes.</p>
<p>Conformism brings order and stability, allowing societies to function smoothly. It facilitates the scaling of power and resources, which can enhance the collective evolutionary fitness of a group.</p>
<p>"Trust the process" works well in the sense that the group can save on computing and decision cost. The catch is that the process must keep working.</p>
<p>So a group of conformist who happened to be lucky enough to follow a right set of values will grow fast enough to destroy the population of a group of deviants who are either busy doing their own thing, or busy disagreeing among themselves.</p>
<p>However, if the conformist values misalign, mistakes cascades and wrong social directions are hard to stop -- the Pied Piper of Hamlin will lead all rats to drown in the river.</p>
<p>Conformism can also be exploited a subset of manipulative deviants, as values get hijacked to benefit a small cabal of deviants (cult leaders and equivalents).</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="evolutionary-disadvantage-of-deviants">Evolutionary disadvantage of deviants<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#evolutionary-disadvantage-of-deviants" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Evolutionary disadvantage of deviants" title="Direct link to Evolutionary disadvantage of deviants">​</a></h2>
<p>Independent thinkers, while often celebrated, <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles">frequently face challenges that conformists do not.</a></p>
<p>While we see glorious success from a selected few independent thinkers and frequently talk about them, it is often the case we are only seeing the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>Many artists, intellectuals, and other independent thinkers struggle financially and in terms of reproductive success. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#user-content-fn-1-a225e9" id="user-content-fnref-1-a225e9" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup>. This raises questions about the evolutionary viability of independent thinking and deviance.</p>
<p>In fact, we could use the market perspective to understand the quantitative tradeoffs and ROI between conformism and independent thinking.</p>
<p>In most advanced economies, the number of salaried workers (conformists) is much higher than the number of entrepreneurs (deviants).</p>
<p>Interestingly, the average earnings of salaried workers is higher than the average earnings of entrepreneurs -- an evidence of the survival advantage of conformism. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#user-content-fn-2-a225e9" id="user-content-fnref-2-a225e9" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup></p>
<p>In ancient China, independent barbarians get defeated or absorbed by the more conforming empire.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="ai-simulations-on-conformism-and-defiance">AI simulations on conformism and defiance<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#ai-simulations-on-conformism-and-defiance" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to AI simulations on conformism and defiance" title="Direct link to AI simulations on conformism and defiance">​</a></h2>
<p>The market perspective used to understand the quantitative tradeoffs between conformism and independent thinking is one way to do it, but we could also use AI simulations to explore the interplay between environmental factors, incentive structures, and behavioral outcomes.</p>
<p>By observing how AI agents respond to different reward functions, we can gain a better understanding of when and why humans might lean towards conformism or independent thinking.</p>
<p>So far, the most interesting AI agents used to simulate human cooperation is the <a href="https://github.com/Axelrod-Python/Axelrod" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Axelrod project</a>.</p>
<p>The discovery is that the greatest survivors are agents who employ "Tit-for-tat" strategies in iterative Prisoner's Dilemma games.</p>
<p>Perhaps, a similar agent simulation could be used to discover the natural bias of agents towards conformism or defiance when status conscious becomes a parameter.</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-a225e9">
<p>Sigh, I knew you would take it the wrong way. I don't mean these people get less sex. Reproduction success in this context is more like the ability to replicate more independent thinkers. So a conformist builds social momentum faster than a deviant. So conformism grows like locusts, while deviance grows like a sequoia. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#user-content-fnref-1-a225e9" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-a225e9">
<p>That doesn't mean you should be a salaried worker for life. I've done a deep macro research explaining how job security is a <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security">debt-financed illusion</a>. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/is-conformism-a-viable-strategy#user-content-fnref-2-a225e9" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>essays</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to steal from the public without public attention]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Today's generation is prosperous. But it's also plagued by problems similar to the past.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today's generation is prosperous. But it's also plagued by problems similar to the past.</p>
<p>Increasing wealth gaps, squeezed middle class, low birth rates, public debts that are increasing unsustainable, difficult job market.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2>
<p>The mainstream narrative now is that the rich have been exploiting the poor, and that all of the problems will go away if only we tax them enough or regulate their profits such that it is no longer predatory. Or, it's a specific race or cabal that is controlling the strings.</p>
<p>The problem with such reasoning is that the antagonist is too obvious. Too many people talk about them, and in fact most of the time people from the past fell for the same narrative. When revolutions end up happening, it wasn't clear if the rich was actually the problem.</p>
<p>In the French Revolution, it's not about the 99% against the 1% as we so commonly believed. It's more like the <a href="https://x.com/GaletteSaw6/status/1892255392987582924/photo/1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">top 1% against the top 0.1%</a>. Most of the common people don't even get represented while they get taken into the violent ride.</p>
<p>Put simply, associating wealth with crime is fallacious. The reason why this narrative gets momentum is because it appeals to the envious. I argue it's in the interest of people who are actually doing the stealing to misdirect public attention away from them to people with big numbers.</p>
<p>How then should one find the dishonest actor that explains all of the present problems and injustice without resorting to sloppy reasoning that matches what the mainstream wants you to antagonize?</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="discovering-the-anatomy-of-the-heist">Discovering the anatomy of the heist<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#discovering-the-anatomy-of-the-heist" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Discovering the anatomy of the heist" title="Direct link to Discovering the anatomy of the heist">​</a></h2>
<p>Most understand that problems and inefficiency don't come out of nowhere, therefore something/someone must be responsible. The next thing to be aware would be if the observed inefficiency is <strong>deliberate</strong> or <strong>accidental</strong>.</p>
<p>Many things that contribute to the growing wealth gap are participated by market players accidentally.</p>
<p>Example, the growth in job complexity and bureaucracy accidentally created wealth gap between those who have exposed themselves to enough cultural capital (through tertiary education) to perform bureaucratic tasks while leaving behind those who cannot afford <a href="https://wcer.wisc.edu/docs/working-papers/Working_Paper_No_2017_2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">tertiary education to gain the cultural capital</a> required to stay compliant to current regulations and complexity demand.</p>
<p>If you look at things objectively, you may understand that dumb regulations and dumb degrees / license to bypass these regulations are the <strong>root of problem as to how some people unjustly got ahead / left behind</strong>. Yet, you hardly hear the mainstream complaining about this problem.</p>
<p>In fact, getting a degree, expecting stricter regulations, and going through very selective labor vetting process has become a cultural dogma that few even draw the connection that this is a possible vector for social division.</p>
<p>On a related topic, the other day I had an argument with my sister about the effectiveness of state education, the most extreme case being China's Gaokao -- The same system that is the <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/22125868211035802?icid=int.sj-abstract.citing-articles.192" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">most unfair and repressive to lower class</a> also happened to <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/China/comments/17334c1/comment/k42ydza/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;utm_term=1&amp;utm_content=share_button" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">get the most support and defense from the lower class</a>.</p>
<p>Gaokao creates "unequal" outcomes and "widening social class," in the sense that it forces the lower class youth to live and think that their life is a predictable grind (IE: another form of serfdom). But to many families, having a child that performs well in state exams is their only lotto to have their social status raised. Their defense to such a system is another example of people "accidentally" creating social division.</p>
<p>In effect, the gaokao system seems to be fall under the a category I would classify as "opportunity stealing hero" (OSH).</p>
<p>If you are convinced that China's gaokao creates net inequality (not through measurements of wealth, but through psychology where competitive students lose their independence of thought to conform to the grind culture), then you'll also find that most state's public education don't do better.</p>
<p><a href="https://educationdata.org/public-education-spending-statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">In US, public schools spend $20k per student</a> for the results of <a href="https://www.thenationalliteracyinstitute.com/post/literacy-statistics-2024-2025-where-we-are-now" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20% illiteracy rate</a>. Acquiring information on YouTube, skillshare will not cost a curious individual more than $500/yr.</p>
<p>If the objective of public education is to increase public literacy and standardized knowledge to promote cultural equality, the results have been opposite -- education administrators are overpaid while young students get dumber and taxpayers get even more broke.</p>
<p>Yet, public educators continue to enjoy powerful political advantages, social returns, and positive public opinion. Another example of OSH.</p>
<p>With 3 examples, we can begin to find the anatomy of the heist by observing the commonalities.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Must have a way to avoid competition</strong>, either through political protection (state education) or high barriers to entry (creating more regulations, requiring higher ranking licenses), etc.</li>
<li><strong>Decisions are undemocratic</strong> (regulations setup by "think tanks" and "experts")</li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/China/comments/17334c1/whats_the_deal_with_chinas_gao_kao/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Victims having "Stockholm syndrome"</strong> to net negative practices</a>. (The hero convinces the victims who had been taken advantage that they in fact benefit from the transaction)</li>
</ul>
<p>With such leads, finding out who else fit such a bill is more productive than being told who is the antagonist.</p>
<p>If you enjoy where your logic will take you, stop scrolling and start thinking and see if your answers match with mine later.</p>
<p>I will do the honors and take the risk of exposing institutions with questionable motive and outcomes.</p>
<p>Here goes.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="shortlisted-bureaucracies">Shortlisted bureaucracies<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#shortlisted-bureaucracies" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Shortlisted bureaucracies" title="Direct link to Shortlisted bureaucracies">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="central-banks">Central banks<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#central-banks" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Central banks" title="Direct link to Central banks">​</a></h3>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="uncompetitive">Uncompetitive<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#uncompetitive" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Uncompetitive" title="Direct link to Uncompetitive">​</a></h4>
<p>Central banks serve as the lender of last resort -- a function that allows them to provide emergency liquidity to banks, thereby forestalling systemic collapse.</p>
<p>But no one else gets this right to create value out of nothing. While it's hard to say they are dishonest, there is no way we can know how accountable too.</p>
<p>In a competitive market, an unaccountable bank would face consequences for poor policies. In central bank's case, mostly its just "bad luck", "bad timing", "oops".</p>
<p>For CB with weaker political power, it is possible for market players to force a competitive decision. (EG: <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskEconomics/comments/altvbm/the_man_who_broke_the_bank_of_england/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">George Soros breaking the BoE by betting against their bad policies</a>)</p>
<p>For stronger CB, especially the US Federal Reserve,
<a href="https://www.econlib.org/yes-monetary-policy-did-cause-the-great-depression/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">it took decades for people to realize and agree some disastrous results done by central banks.</a></p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="undemocratic">Undemocratic<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#undemocratic" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Undemocratic" title="Direct link to Undemocratic">​</a></h4>
<p><a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/faqs/about_12591.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The public cannot elect a Fed Chair; the selection process is conducted behind closed doors with little transparency</a> -- comparable in its secrecy to the election of a pope.</p>
<p>The Fed Chair can make policies that influence credit markets such that it directly kills business or raise portfolio value.</p>
<p><a href="https://sites.lsa.umich.edu/mje/2023/09/04/why-the-2-inflation-target/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The 2% inflation target is a dogma, not an expert research or public agreement.</a> I can read the whole link to you. Or I can just tell you it's all vibes.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enough-victims-with-stockholm">Enough victims with Stockholm.<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#enough-victims-with-stockholm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enough victims with Stockholm." title="Direct link to Enough victims with Stockholm.">​</a></h4>
<p>Many are “victimized” by policies done by CB. If you own cash, the real value of their money is eroded by inflation.</p>
<p>Yet, most can't reject this poison, especially if you are an office workers with state contracts (where do you think the state gets their money to pay your contract work?), is a homeowners whose asset values grow together with each successive rounds of money printing.</p>
<p>If you work in office, your employment is likely an illusion. They will still raise back enough taxes from you to make back the money they printed to pay you <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-1-e68ca5" id="user-content-fnref-1-e68ca5" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup>. If you have any more left to spend, they will devalue it by printing the next round of money.</p>
<p>We become unwitting “Stockholmers” by growing psychologically dependent on a system that also steals from us.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="human-resources-and-recruiting-industry">Human resources and recruiting industry<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#human-resources-and-recruiting-industry" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Human resources and recruiting industry" title="Direct link to Human resources and recruiting industry">​</a></h3>
<p>(<em>There is a whole rabbit hole known as "executive recruiting" that is not covered in this article. Right now I'll just focus on the normal recruiting industry we all know and love.</em>)</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="anticompetitive">Anticompetitive<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#anticompetitive" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Anticompetitive" title="Direct link to Anticompetitive">​</a></h4>
<blockquote>
<p>Have you met a department that is in charge of firing and hiring HR?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A great recruiter should be paid by the quality of candidates they hire. In practice, recruiters get paid by the number of candidates they closed.</p>
<p>This means there is no pressure to properly vet for candidates for employers, or no pressure to help job seekers land jobs. You pay your LinkedIn Premium and they play you for a fool.</p>
<p>In more competitive markets, there is a "money back guarantee" for people who are unsatisfied with the product.  A simple way to make HR competitive is to also have a "money back guarantee" system, where the recruiter forfeits their commission if the candidate is bad, or if the candidate couldn't find a job.</p>
<p>Why don't we do it?</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="undemocratic-1">Undemocratic<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#undemocratic-1" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Undemocratic" title="Direct link to Undemocratic">​</a></h4>
<p>HR and recruitment comes up with lots of policies that have consequential effects to the market, yet they are not subjected to the agreement of their customers.</p>
<p>For example, HR policies routinely use expensive educational degrees as prerequisites for roles -- even when the actual performance gap between degree holders and non-degree holders is negligible in many real-world contexts.</p>
<p>In effect, HR legitimizes the value of expensive educational degrees simply by using it as a prerequisite to the roles they have. This isn't problematic if educational degrees do actually have value as a competency signal.</p>
<p>To find out if degrees, licenses, or other credentials are actually a competency signal, a scientific method would be to look at the data by systematically measuring the quality of both recruits and rejects using an objective function.</p>
<p><strong>I have hardly met any HR that does this</strong> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-2-e68ca5" id="user-content-fnref-2-e68ca5" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>It doesn't help that degree standards are getting lower while jobs are getting more complex. These days, the performance gap of degree owners and non-degree owners are negligible in the real world.</p>
<p>Degrees now function more like a "ticket you buy for the chance to work" that <a href="https://www.greeneuropeanjournal.eu/pierre-bourdieu-cultural-capital-in-the-21st-century/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">gatekeeps labor supply to include only those who can afford a 4 year hiatus and 100k expense.</a></p>
<p>HR could easily fix their poor policy by simply letting themselves subjected to a scientific method, where they measure the quality of their recruits and the lack of quality of their rejects. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy">I've suggested a simple way to do it.</a></p>
<p>Yet, there is simply no market, competitive, moral pressure to do so.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="victims-with-stockholm">Victims with Stockholm<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#victims-with-stockholm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Victims with Stockholm" title="Direct link to Victims with Stockholm">​</a></h4>
<p>Business owners, shareholders, and job seekers think we are better off with them.</p>
<p>What people don't ask is how many of the problems the HR / recruitment industry solves are problems created by a bureacracy (that recruiters themselves are part of).</p>
<p>Example: employment rights, unions, protection of workers supposedly protect workers from unfair labor practices (Stockholm warning). But this also make it much harder for business owners to hire and fire employees, thus justifying the need for HR / recruiters.</p>
<p>The 2nd order effect is that business are less willing to hire and invest in employees, given that underperforming employees are so hard to let go.</p>
<p>I can't make the call that we are better off without labor regulations. But its important to understand the more complex we make labor laws, the more power HR and recruiters get.</p>
<p>At some point, job seekers lose and business owners lose.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="faq">FAQ<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#faq" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to FAQ" title="Direct link to FAQ">​</a></h2>
<blockquote>
<p>"Is it a "middleman problem"?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I believe most of the bad things in life are not intentional. It's very rare to meet someone with a mission to cause as much damage as they can while getting away with it.</p>
<p>This means its important to inspect for systems that are supposedly "good" but at some point stop serving the interest of the system consumer.</p>
<p>What I notice is that problems that are so complicated to need a middleman tends to attract "careerist"<sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-3-e68ca5" id="user-content-fnref-3-e68ca5" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup> to setup uncompetitive bureaucracy (IE: rent-seeking toll).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"But aren't the rich the real final boss?"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's too convenient, too big of the brush, and often results in bad policies. Instead, I think it's more helpful to expose people to the anatomy of how institutions can take advantage of the public.</p>
<p>So long as the public are uncritical about their practices, the bureacracy can keep masquerading as a value-creator when its a parasite <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fn-4-e68ca5" id="user-content-fnref-4-e68ca5" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup>.</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-e68ca5">
<p>Interestingly, <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/articles/tax/10/history-taxes.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">federal income taxes we paid for granted started when the CB was invented at 1913</a>. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-1-e68ca5" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-e68ca5">
<p>I've spoke around recruiters during informal settings. In most of my conversations with recruiters, the best indicator of a good candidate is "what other recruiters" say about them. In logical settings, this is known as "circular reasoning". It's as unscientific as "just vibes". Yeah, you think people who make important decisions are more responsibile. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-2-e68ca5" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-e68ca5">
<p>Career usually mean something better than job and supposedly requires more respect. But rent-seeking can also be a career. The question is should the public sponsor such careers? <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-3-e68ca5" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4-e68ca5">
<p>Parasite is a strong word, but the classification is that it must grow infinitely at the expense of the host's strength. This is consistent with my observations. The Fed gets stronger everytime they print more money and do not hesitate to increase their personnel. Similarly, HR went from 0.5% workforce to 1.5% workforce from 1980 to 2020. In the same time with the growth of these institutions, their "customers" get weaker. This is unlike competitive economic systems (example Nvidia) where their growth is also followed by the growth in strength by their customers. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-steal-from-the-public#user-content-fnref-4-e68ca5" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>essays</category>
            <category>recruitment</category>
            <category>hiring</category>
            <category>economics</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The real function of taxes]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Taxes are dumb.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taxes are dumb.</p>
<p>It's hard to be controversial to say so. Most people who worked and earned money for a living would be frustrated by the whole experience that is so embedded in modern society, to the point it becomes something we learned to be helpless about.</p>
<p>This post won't try to change the way taxes work. I'm too small of a player for the legal system to give a damn about. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-1-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-1-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<p>That said, I can explain how taxes work in a way that the common person will learn, and people can decide if taxes are worth it.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="modern-monetary-theory">Modern monetary theory<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#modern-monetary-theory" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Modern monetary theory" title="Direct link to Modern monetary theory">​</a></h2>
<p>Modern money is all fiat, meaning it is not backed by anything. Not gold, not oil, just blind trust. Actually, it is backed by the power of military<sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-2-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-2-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup>, but we will leave the story to another day.</p>
<p>If we are to accept that money is not backed by anything, a state theoretically doesn't need to collect taxes before they spend -- they can just spend on what they want and pay it back later by raising taxes, or to do nothing and devalue all cash and savings.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-bother-collecting-taxes">"Why bother collecting taxes?"<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#why-bother-collecting-taxes" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Why bother collecting taxes?&quot;" title="Direct link to &quot;Why bother collecting taxes?&quot;">​</a></h3>
<p>Great question. The amount of effort it takes to collect taxes is enormous.</p>
<p>Using the US as an example (its the most available one to build my priors) <a href="https://taxfoundation.org/data/all/federal/irs-tax-compliance-costs/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the estimates of tax compliance cost of the $546 billion, or nearly 2 percent of GDP.</a></p>
<p>Annually, the US government raises <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/FYFRGDA188S" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">17% of GDP as taxes</a>.</p>
<p>In effect, we are spending $15 for every $100 we harass a productive business to give the state.</p>
<p>This number includes taxes paid through active means (IRS audits) and passive means (taxes on income, VAT). If we are to estimate the cost of active collection and the actual tax revenue active collectors raised, it may be less than the cost it takes to finance active collectors.</p>
<p>It's like spending $100 on debt collectors (debt isn't even a right word as it implies we owe the state our production) to raise something less than $100.</p>
<p>If the objective of taxes is really to raise capital to afford projects, active collection seems ineffective at what they do.</p>
<p>Instead of answering why are we doing something inefficient, let's start with what happens if we just do nothing.</p>
<hr>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="case-1-really-doing-nothing">Case 1: Really doing nothing<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#case-1-really-doing-nothing" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Case 1: Really doing nothing" title="Direct link to Case 1: Really doing nothing">​</a></h3>
<p>No government spending, no taxes, constant supply of money. The state is literally sleeping at the wheel.</p>
<p>Unrealistic scenario, but suppose this happens we should predict inflation to be 0%. This seems like a time when we have a perfect currency.</p>
<p>The problem is that the economy becomes perfectly competitive, which means those that earn will hold more currency and control a bigger share of the network (mercantilism).</p>
<p>The currency becomes less representative to those who are weaker or less competitive. With no state spending, there is no safety net except for private charities.</p>
<p>If people expect spending will cause them to lose power to sellers, then transactions are seen as zero-sum and the economy gets more illiquid.</p>
<p>Also, not having a state is really a bad idea, in the sense that markets become lawless. In practice what you'll end up getting is local mafias bullying businesses into giving them special privileges -- you don't pay taxes to the state, but you pay "taxes" to guys meaner than you. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-5-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-5-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="case-2-doing-anything-the-state-wants">Case 2: Doing anything the state wants<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#case-2-doing-anything-the-state-wants" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Case 2: Doing anything the state wants" title="Direct link to Case 2: Doing anything the state wants">​</a></h3>
<p>State prints as much money as it wants, gives out as much to anyone who will vote for them. Never collects any of them back.</p>
<p>Sounds too good to be true. Now people stop producing because there is no reason to. When there is no production, all the money can't buy anything -- you have a hyperinflation situation.</p>
<p>There's more! When people expect the currency to get weaker, the network of producers becomes more reluctant to accept the currency -- people rather do a barter trade or keep good things for themselves than to take your currency.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="case-3-spend-now-collect-back-everything-later">Case 3: Spend now, collect back everything later<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#case-3-spend-now-collect-back-everything-later" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Case 3: Spend now, collect back everything later" title="Direct link to Case 3: Spend now, collect back everything later">​</a></h3>
<p>The "perfect" scenario. The state spends as much as it wants to get something done, then get back all the money it spent back from people through taxes.</p>
<p>No net inflation, and stuff gets done! What's the problem?</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="there-is-always-a-better-deal">There is always a better deal<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#there-is-always-a-better-deal" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to There is always a better deal" title="Direct link to There is always a better deal">​</a></h4>
<p>There is a more perfect scenario -- stuff gets done, and people keep all the newly minted currency. If something valuable was already done, why waste energy to give back the catalyst (ie: the currency)?</p>
<p>The problem happens when the currency gets spent on more things than it was made to spend on (IE: buying labor for social services becomes salary to spend and compete on limited goods) -- Taxes ensures the velocity of created money is not infinite.</p>
<p>In practice people can always argue why they don't need to return the currency, so its hard to take back as much money as we created.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="whose-stuff-gets-done">Whose stuff gets done?<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#whose-stuff-gets-done" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Whose stuff gets done?" title="Direct link to Whose stuff gets done?">​</a></h4>
<p>The state can create money to buy for things they want, but in practice you can bet the decisions aren't fair (IE: what the state wants to buy might not be what the people want to buy).</p>
<p>In fact, the state can just set up a shell company with their entourage, print some money and pay his friends and declaring his friends are being "paid to do social work". -- This is wastage in a nutshell.</p>
<p>In practice, things are not so blatant. Its more likely for state actors to set up lots of layers of agency that takes some cut of the budget, where the agency also happens to contain a share of the state's entourage -- also known as "deep state".</p>
<p>So a scenario with perfect balance sheet is not perfect if the work paid to do / things bought isn't representative.</p>
<h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="crowding-out">Crowding out<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#crowding-out" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Crowding out" title="Direct link to Crowding out">​</a></h4>
<p>If the state prints money to hire workers, then it means someone else would lose the worker they wanted to hire to do their work.</p>
<p>In a free market, the most important work gets done first and that is reflected by prices and bids.</p>
<p>When the state spends money, it is unclear if the work that needs to be done are the most important ones.</p>
<p>When suboptimal decisions are made and financed, in effect that is also a net loss to the people. It's like saying you win 10% doing something when you could have won 50% doing nothing -- a good outcome is not a valid defense for a good decision.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="its-all-decisions">It's all decisions<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#its-all-decisions" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to It's all decisions" title="Direct link to It's all decisions">​</a></h2>
<p>Notice the theme here. The state can do anything it wants, but its decisions must be sound (IE: logical, benefits the people, within budget).</p>
<p>A sound decision is one that is profitable. IE: You spend little to do a lot.</p>
<p>When the state does something suboptimal, the net effect is the people's standard of living will devalue because they:</p>
<ol>
<li>need to ask more taxes from the people to pay back what they spent.</li>
<li>print more money to pay back what they spent, creating inflation.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>In modern finance, taxes are paid so inflation does not happen.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="why-not-just-let-inflation-happen">"Why not just let inflation happen?"<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#why-not-just-let-inflation-happen" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Why not just let inflation happen?&quot;" title="Direct link to &quot;Why not just let inflation happen?&quot;">​</a></h2>
<p>Great question. If the net effect of ineffective state spending is lower standards of living, and the way it is delivered can be either passive (through inflation) or active (through taxes), we could choose to do nothing.</p>
<p>Why go through all the hassle and trouble to feel pain?</p>
<p>I could write a whole post on how money works, how it flows. But the short answer I discovered after 20 years of studying money is: "it's all politics".</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You will never understand bureaucracies until you understand that for bureaucrats procedure is everything and outcomes are nothing. -- Thomas Sowell</p>
</blockquote>
<p>While the post is critical about taxes, there are some cases when it can make sense... <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-3-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-3-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-4-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-4-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">5</a></sup></p>
<p>However, rather than trying so hard to raise taxes, there is a better way...</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="stop-spending-other-peoples-money-on-stupid-stuff">"Stop spending (other people's) money on stupid stuff"<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#stop-spending-other-peoples-money-on-stupid-stuff" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to &quot;Stop spending (other people's) money on stupid stuff&quot;" title="Direct link to &quot;Stop spending (other people's) money on stupid stuff&quot;">​</a></h2>
<p>People think public spending is free money. I've already shown you that public spending takes back money through taxes or inflation -- it is just financial physics.</p>
<p>The reason why people think public spending is free money -- that voters consistently vote for money spending across any civilization -- I suspect has to do with "semantic deception".</p>
<p>If people really understood how public spending gets paid back, perhaps they wouldn't be so obsessed with the idea of "free money". The issue is that the sematics "public spending" gives people the idea that it is "money spent on the public", so we just ignored all the little things that happen behind the scenes.</p>
<p>The same "semantic deception" can happen in things like "trust and safety team" <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-6-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-6-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">6</a></sup> , "conservative and liberal" <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-7-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-7-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">7</a></sup>, "as a matter of fact" <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fn-8-4c6868" id="user-content-fnref-8-4c6868" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">8</a></sup>.</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-4c6868">
<p>if you can't see what I did there, I'm disappointed. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-1-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-4c6868">
<p>Modern fiat currencies aren't entirely worthless. Typically currency is legitimized through public confidence. A currency that can be printed endlessly would mean more people opting out of the network. But confidence is fragile and fluctuates, so a mandate and force is more reliable. You will notice that reserve currencies tend to be controlled by contries with the strongest military. It is no coincidence. Having a gun means you accept whatever value there is on the paper. This is also a short story why I think cryptocurrencies are unviable. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-2-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-5-4c6868">
<p>The irony is that by electing a state to keep mafias away, a state can eventually grow big enough to be a "mafia" itself, in the sense they bully people into compliance through "legal" and "financial" means (by manipulating currencies). <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-5-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-4c6868">
<p>Unlike inflation that erodes power indiscrimately, taxes are are more targeted to specific people. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-3-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4-4c6868">
<p>There is a perspective where taxes make sense, like a "subscription" to the government. Some people uses more public services, like roads, hospital. So higher taxes are like your "silver, gold, platinum" subscription tiers. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-4-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 5" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-6-4c6868">
<p>Many times whatever they do has nothing to do with trust or safety. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-6-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 6" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-7-4c6868">
<p>The word <code>conservative</code> artificially signals someone to be close-minded, <code>liberal</code> an open-minded. But you find that the signal isn't any reliable. People who get manipulated by semantic deception would falsely believe a liberal to be more open-minded than a conservative. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-7-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 7" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-8-4c6868">
<p>The word "fact" artificially signals the truth or veracity of the statement and is commonly used as a <a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/w/semantic-stopsign" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">semantic stopsign</a>. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/real-function-of-taxes#user-content-fnref-8-4c6868" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 8" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>economics</category>
            <category>finance</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why independent people invite troubles]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I am surrounded by independent thinkers.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am surrounded by independent thinkers. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-1-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-1-0f5506" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<p>From this limited sampling, I learn that most of these independent thinkers had an episode of being misunderstood, disagreed, or ridiculed by the people around them.</p>
<p>Given that society generally prefers conformity, those who stand out or question the status quo are generally meet resistance from social exclusion to hostility.</p>
<p>This is also a common trope in anime, movies, videogames, pop content we consume -- where the protagonists are often portrayed as independent people who frequently invite opposition and antagonists.</p>
<p>We come to take for granted that this is just the way it is and think nothing about it. Perhaps its just a "main character syndrome", where everyone universally has the same experience of rejection, its just that only the survivors get to tell their story and the rest of us romanticize those misunderstandings and adversity.</p>
<p>This romanticization, while inspiring, obscures the fact that the experiences of independent people are not unique or extraordinary but rather a common consequence of their nonconformity.</p>
<p>I believe there is a structural reason why anyone who attempts to be independent will meet opposition and social challenges, and is very uncommon for independent people to be ignored or celebrated. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-2-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-2-0f5506" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">2</a></sup></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="a-conformist-cant-be-disagreed">A conformist can't be disagreed<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#a-conformist-cant-be-disagreed" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to A conformist can't be disagreed" title="Direct link to A conformist can't be disagreed">​</a></h2>
<p>Simply because a conformist's reward function is to be agreed. If they ever get disagreed, they will just shift their ideas to what is conventionally accepted.</p>
<p>By sampling bias, it means deviants will experience 90% of all disagreements. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-5-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-5-0f5506" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="deviant-minds-are-easy-targets">Deviant minds are easy targets<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#deviant-minds-are-easy-targets" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Deviant minds are easy targets" title="Direct link to Deviant minds are easy targets">​</a></h2>
<p>A deviant often become easy targets for those seeking to enhance their social reputation.</p>
<p>Opposing the establishment, especially in fields like politics is a braindead strategy to gain attention and support.</p>
<p>For example, political candidates may rise to power simply by positioning themselves as opponents of the existing order, without necessarily offering substantial or innovative policies.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cZG95grO-vc&amp;ab_channel=Japanalysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The case of Tachibana Takeshi is a great illustration</a>. His political ascent was primarily fueled by his opposition to the NHK fee -- a stance that resonated with many who were dissatisfied with the status quo. However, once in power, it became evident that his strategy, politics, and philosophy lacked depth and he lost his momentum after "the dragon has been slain".</p>
<p>The point is "braindead opposition strategy" against any target that sticks out is very rewarding, and deviants unintentionally create opportunities for others to gain prominence by simply opposing them.</p>
<p>The act of contradicting a deviant is low-risk / high-reward behavior, making deviants easy targets for those seeking to elevate their own social standing.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="changing-minds-forces-people-to-reflect-on-weaknesses">Changing minds forces people to reflect on weaknesses<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#changing-minds-forces-people-to-reflect-on-weaknesses" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Changing minds forces people to reflect on weaknesses" title="Direct link to Changing minds forces people to reflect on weaknesses">​</a></h2>
<p>Acting as a messenger of truth or promoting independent ideas is high risk. It is much simpler and less risky for individuals to conform to the majority opinion than to challenge it.</p>
<p>When deviants change people's minds, they encounter resistance because their message forces others to confront their own vulnerabilities or mistakes.</p>
<p>This can lead to defensive reactions, as individuals feel compelled to double down on their established positions to avoid appearing wrong.</p>
<p>This dynamic is even more obvious in institutional settings, where admitting the validity of an deviant's ideas means rejecting the institution they are part of -- it is an equivalent of being placed in an "ideological death ground" if one has a career or is dependent on the survival of the institution.</p>
<p>In cases of a person being placed in "death grounds", the pushback is desperate, regardless of how right a deviant's ideas are.</p>
<p>In most cases, the pushback is directed to the deviant itself, regardless of how much this antagonism is justified.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="it-is-inevitable-for-deviants-to-invite-trouble">It is inevitable for deviants to invite trouble<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#it-is-inevitable-for-deviants-to-invite-trouble" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to It is inevitable for deviants to invite trouble" title="Direct link to It is inevitable for deviants to invite trouble">​</a></h2>
<p>So long as we have a social dynamic that rewards reputation and conformity, status consciousness becomes an investment with ROI. Then, being a deviant inherently invites trouble.</p>
<p>It is not that any individual personal have an issue against deviants -- most individuals would prefer interacting with a deviant over conformists.</p>
<p>However, the social system finds it easy to penalize deviants because status consciousness means some agent find their ranking and rewards threatened by uncommon behaviors. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-4-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-4-0f5506" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">4</a></sup></p>
<p>The act of questioning norms or presenting alternative viewpoints disrupts the equilibrium and can threaten the reputation of those invested in maintaining the status quo.</p>
<p>I'll argue that due to this dynamic, <strong>it is impossible for anyone to have true independent thinking unless they have complete detachment from status consciousness.</strong> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-3-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-3-0f5506" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">5</a></sup> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-6-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-6-0f5506" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">6</a></sup> <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-7-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-7-0f5506" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">7</a></sup></p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="tldr">TLDR<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#tldr" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to TLDR" title="Direct link to TLDR">​</a></h2>
<p>Deviants invite troubles because challenging the status quo disrupts social dynamics and threatens the reputation of those who benefit from the existing order.</p>
<p>The obstacles faced by deviants are not always personal and its more likely rooted in human nature and the structures of society.</p>
<p>While independence is crucial for innovation and progress, it comes at a cost that not everyone is willing or able to bear.</p>
<p>To all deviants: Don't be a drama queen and think everyone is out there to get you. Everyone is "out there to get you" because that is what people do. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fn-5-0f5506" id="user-content-fnref-5-0f5506-2" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">3</a></sup></p>
<p>Get over it and keep working.</p>
<hr>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-0f5506">
<p>if you can't see what I did there, I'm disappointed. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-1-0f5506" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-2-0f5506">
<p>There are cases of autistic people who can do own thing competently and oblivious to the negativity or oppositions of others. While such ignorance means they are not held back by public opinion, it is still more probable their avant-garde work meets more resistance relative to support. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-2-0f5506" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-5-0f5506">
<p>Inversely, it could mean any person who experienced a chronic disagreements are more likely to see themselves as a deviant -- this is fallacy thinking. Someone who is consistently disagreed may see themselves as a deviant, but that <strong>doesn't mean they are not a conformist.</strong> A conformist can keep saying the wrong thing, be disagreed by a diverse group of people, and they will wrongly imagine that they are a deviant and the rest are conformist. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-5-0f5506" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a> <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-5-0f5506-2" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 3-2" class="data-footnote-backref">↩<sup>2</sup></a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-4-0f5506">
<p>In cases of a group of people who don't compare with one another, you notice that independent behaviors don't meet as much rejections as these groups have no status games to play with one another. Since neither cares much about their own reputation, another person's action doesn't bring them any threat and you observe less "witch-hunting" behavior. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-4-0f5506" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 4" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-3-0f5506">
<p>A simple observation is to observe artists and their behavior pre-fame and post-fame. An artist is an embodiment of independence. But anyone who observes an artist that rises to fame is that they become less controversial the more popular they are. If my theory is true, artists who gets less controversial become like that because they have more interest in developing status consciousness. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-3-0f5506" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 5" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-6-0f5506">
<p>I expect pushback for saying this, but I think this reason also explains why creative women are less common than creative men. Women are more status conscious, so there is a disadvantage in the capacity to hold independent thoughts. That is not to say women are less creative -- a woman who is detached from status conscious are just as capable of being creative. Inversely, a man that is burdened by status-conscious will have as much trouble being creative. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-6-0f5506" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 6" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
<li id="user-content-fn-7-0f5506">
<p>This theory also support the observation that many great art in ancient history was done by non-hetero people (Michelangelo, Nikola Tesla). But as LGBTQ and DEI gathers more social momentum and subsequently more conformist, you see a decline in the quality of art produced by non-hetero people if they happen to be absorbed by the conformist movement (Snow White and Concord are the latest disasters). <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/why-independent-people-invite-troubles#user-content-fnref-7-0f5506" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 7" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>essays</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We can't afford job security]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[If you understand government budgets, you will stop believing in job security.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you understand government budgets, you will stop believing in job security.</p>
<p>There is no such thing as job security -- especially not in a role without craftsmanship -- without taking away freedom from future generations.</p>
<p>Why? Because most people's idea of "job security" requires them to be a high paying white-collar bureaucrat in an office with a big corner desk.</p>
<p>Who wants to have a secure job that needs you to deal with dirt, danger, difficulties? If you can handle those 3Ds I guarantee your career is secure 100%. Incidentally, those are the jobs people look forward the most to be replaced.</p>
<p>Therefore, the reality is not that there is "no job security", rather it is "there is not enough non-3D secure jobs" in this world, because each one requires a government or bureaucracy to print or devalue existing currency to keep you and your desk.</p>
<p>When everyone thinks they are entitled to that illusion, what do you think is going to happen to future generations?</p>
<p>Some people worked hard to get a cushy, secure job as a C-level in some corporate, public office, conglomerate, consultancy, education institution.</p>
<p>An average person will think the price is decades of hard work climbing the career ladder and dealing with occasional office politics -- it is not the only price paid.</p>
<p>If the job is an administrative role where the "ascension" requires building a wall to keep off competitors (EG: adding regulations, raising licensing requirements to limit labor supply), paper pushing (office equivalent of digging a hole then filling a hole), it may be complicit in making some of the younger generations less free in doing productive work and less free with their social mobility.</p>
<p>If you ever felt "credential inflation" and lower conversion rates in job application rates, this is what's happening and you have the market that existed before you to thank.</p>
<p>If you are still young and starting out in your career, stop buying the idea or complaining about job security -- it was never there.</p>
<p>If it was, then the (money printing and deficit spending) ship has sailed and you need to start making something for yourself.</p>
<p>Look up your state's public spending, learn how to read financial statements of companies, and learn how money and value is created. You will quickly come to conclusion the only way wealth can be created is to do something that helps people and do it better (IE: getting better at your craft).</p>
<p>Most office jobs today are "state manufactured elites". IE: the state lends money for someone to get into college, get in debt, then offers them to be a slave for the state.</p>
<p>It is as ridiculous as minting your own crypto, selling "scholarships" to players by borrowing them your axoloties, and sending those axolotl to battle as a chore. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security#user-content-fn-1-a568d0" id="user-content-fnref-1-a568d0" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<p>The difference is one does it with fictional currency. The other does it with printed or taxed money.</p>
<p><a href="https://medium.datadriveninvestor.com/the-last-bullet-how-modern-finance-has-stole-enough-from-its-youth-2f2988b7b30a" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">If you think its unsustainable, we are very close to the end of line.</a></p>
<p>If you want real job security, you must accept 3Ds, or be so good at your craft that no one beats you at your game.</p>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-a568d0">
<p>If you are wondering, it's Axie Infinity. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/we-cant-afford-job-security#user-content-fnref-1-a568d0" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>economics</category>
            <category>finance</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to test your recruiting strategy]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA["It's so hard to find talent." -- company]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>"It's so hard to find talent." -- company</p>
<p>"The job market for SWE is cooked." -- Software engineers 2024</p>
<p>Logically, that can't be possible. But nothing in real life is perfectly logical. As engineers we need to diagnose and fix the problems.</p>
<p>In software, we have things like unit test, integrated test, system test.</p>
<p>As it complexity goes higher, we need live simulations, like hiring a game tester or setup Selenium to simulate a login process.</p>
<p>With the same philosophy, a company could hypothetically perform "recruiting test" that is really easy to do.</p>
<hr>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="recruiting-test-no-one-does">Recruiting test (no one does)<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#recruiting-test-no-one-does" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Recruiting test (no one does)" title="Direct link to Recruiting test (no one does)">​</a></h2>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-1-create-a-fictional-profile">Step 1: Create a fictional profile<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#step-1-create-a-fictional-profile" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 1: Create a fictional profile" title="Direct link to Step 1: Create a fictional profile">​</a></h3>
<p>with the ideal resume for the position you're trying to recruit.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="step-2-let-your-own-recruiter-call-back-your-resume">Step 2: Let your own recruiter call back your resume.<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#step-2-let-your-own-recruiter-call-back-your-resume" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Step 2: Let your own recruiter call back your resume." title="Direct link to Step 2: Let your own recruiter call back your resume.">​</a></h3>
<p>If it doesn't get past the phone screen, your recruiters are not doing their job.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="proper-scientific-method">Proper scientific method<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/how-to-test-your-recruiting-strategy#proper-scientific-method" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Proper scientific method" title="Direct link to Proper scientific method">​</a></h3>
<p>If you have to do it scientifically, create 10 or 2-10% of applications with those profile. Do not announce to your recruiters you have this much "qualified simulated accounts" so the <a href="https://builtin.com/data-science/train-test-split" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">test set is not included in training</a>.</p>
<p>Check how much they missed as a benchmark, say 7/10 to measure you screening false negative rate.</p>
<p>You will solve the tech job shortage + tech unemployment.</p>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>"It's going to waste 20 minutes of my life and phone call!"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You waste months of life on a wrong hire. If your CEO picks up the phone just say congrats you done your work.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Creating and maintaining fictional profiles is so hard!"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone is using AI to generate their profiles already. They are also including as many frameworks (they are not even good at) as they can in resumes to hack the ATS keyword search.</p>
<p>Instead of investing on data science to figure out a better recruiting AI, use cheap data science to test your recruitment hit rate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"It makes a lot of sense but we don't want to do it"</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://x.com/upstatefederlst/status/1872125343508971847" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">That's how we get tweets like this. </a></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>recruitment</category>
            <category>hiring</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Less is more]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/less-is-more</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/less-is-more</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In any given business, the ideal state is that you can get away doing the least while creating the most outcome. In practice, idling looks like wasted cost, lost revenue. This philosophy is the result of us getting conditioned by centuries of economic model where labor time can be valued economically.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In any given business, the ideal state is that you can get away doing the least while creating the most outcome. In practice, idling looks like wasted cost, lost revenue. This philosophy is the result of us getting conditioned by centuries of economic model where labor time can be valued economically.</p>
<p>It is hard escaping being a victim to this hustling mentality, where simply believing that if one can put in more hours one would be achieving more -- this view get more wrong with every progress made to automation and technology.</p>
<hr>
<p>When I'm composing music, in any given moment not all instruments are busy playing their own notes, yet somehow they are still able to create an "effective symphony" with so little activity from each individual.</p>
<p>In fact, to achieve an effective symphony, it is necessary for pauses, emphasis, and passing spotlights to different parts and performers of the orchestra.</p>
<p>The best composers or conductors don't make everyone play all the time. When I was an amateur, I thought the requirement to be a good composer is complexity, difficulty, and novelty, yet I notice a lot of great composers can get away with composition that is simple to play (C-major), cliched progressions (4/4 time signature) (1-4-5-6 progression) and still hitting the top charts.</p>
<p>Inversely, a composition that is played by all parts of the orchestra constantly with complex maneuver are actually works done by an amateur. With the advent of digital music, it is now possible for composers to write in range and complexity that are impossible to perform.</p>
<hr>
<p>If difficulty and activity are signs of skill, then music topping the charts would have been electronic music with 10 instruments playing throughout the song at 200 BPM, with SFX automation clips stacked over one another. Clearly, the playlists we choose don't look like this.</p>
<p>Given the lack of correlation (that is continuing to decrease) between activity and outcome, somehow businesses and people who want to improve their personal career are still stuck with the mindset that "activity &gt;&gt; outcome".</p>
<p>Somehow, it is unacceptable for any employee to not have a backlog full of events. It is shameful to be seen by your friends that you don't have a full schedule one month ahead of you. You look like a loser if you don't have anything going on during your weekends or holidays.</p>
<p>Ask any artist, software developer, writer that is competent, and they always seem to arrive to the same answer-- effective emptiness, blanks, and space is required in a finished good product.</p>
<p>I think management and hustlers have a lot to learn from these people.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>management</category>
            <category>business</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Anatomy of Ineffective leaders]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Over 10 years of being someone's worker, leaders that own those characters demonstrate worse track records in company performance than leaders that don't have those characteristics.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over 10 years of being someone's worker, leaders that own those characters demonstrate worse track records in company performance than leaders that don't have those characteristics.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="speculating-on-stocks-or-futures">Speculating on stocks or futures<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#speculating-on-stocks-or-futures" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Speculating on stocks or futures" title="Direct link to Speculating on stocks or futures">​</a></h2>
<p>A leader should spend all their time creating and engineering a better future. Speculating on markets outside their expertise should be a waste of time if they really know what they are doing.</p>
<p>Even lower confidence if I peeked at their portfolio and notice them losing trades on speculative assets. Is that the reason why my boss urgently needs money and productivity?</p>
<p>There are some exceptions, where a great investor is also doing the hands-on work of running a company. <sup><a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#user-content-fn-1-747160" id="user-content-fnref-1-747160" data-footnote-ref="true" aria-describedby="footnote-label">1</a></sup></p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="threatens-misbehaving-employees-with-pay-cut-and-termination">Threatens misbehaving employees with pay cut and termination<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#threatens-misbehaving-employees-with-pay-cut-and-termination" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Threatens misbehaving employees with pay cut and termination" title="Direct link to Threatens misbehaving employees with pay cut and termination">​</a></h2>
<p>If an employee is a problem and you can do without them, terminate. Don't need to threaten.</p>
<p>If you must threaten, intimidation is a poor strategy to motivate someone who is underperforming or misbehaving -- a leader that makes a poor strategy is a poor leader.</p>
<p>What happens when you threaten is resentment and people preparing to jump ship as soon as they find the opportunity. Bad retention strategy.</p>
<p>Roll for persuasion, not intimidation.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="not-respectful-of-other-peoples-time">Not respectful of other people's time<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#not-respectful-of-other-peoples-time" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Not respectful of other people's time" title="Direct link to Not respectful of other people's time">​</a></h2>
<p>By showing up late, or keeping people overtime on projects or meetings.</p>
<p>Usually, this behavior is confounded with regular poor business judgment.</p>
<p>They tend to have budget issues and lack of manpower issues, but I hypothesize the true cause is that they cannot properly allocate priorities.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="underpays-or-too-much-cost-cutting">Underpays or too much cost-cutting<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#underpays-or-too-much-cost-cutting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Underpays or too much cost-cutting" title="Direct link to Underpays or too much cost-cutting">​</a></h2>
<p>You don't build a sports team that wins by buying players at wholesale prices. Lots of people do it, but I haven't seen one that works.</p>
<p>If someone really had a good solution to your problem, you pay as much as you can to get it.</p>
<p>Underpaying and cost-cutting is also a behavior that's confounded with priority issues similar to (3).</p>
<p>Underpaying, while it works against workers who are desperate enough to put up with those conditions, also has the effect of hiding the real costs of the problem.</p>
<p>Leaders will take for granted that this is all the investment that needs to get things done (at unsustainable prices) and think they have margins to pursue even worse market ideas.</p>
<p>You don't win from someone's losses by lowballing. You also lose out on real information that would have stopped you from pursuing bad ideas.</p>
<!-- -->
<section data-footnotes="true" class="footnotes"><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7 sr-only" id="footnote-label">Footnotes<a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#footnote-label" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Footnotes" title="Direct link to Footnotes">​</a></h2>
<ol>
<li id="user-content-fn-1-747160">
<p>In rare cases, I met leaders who are great investors and they are great people to work with as they understand macro, accounting, and good business models. I hold suspicion to leaders who are responsible for a large part of the company and its workers future, but somehow find time for short-term derivatives and engage with trading systems they cannot explain. <a href="https://neldivad.github.io/blog/ineffective-leaders#user-content-fnref-1-747160" data-footnote-backref="" aria-label="Back to reference 1" class="data-footnote-backref">↩</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>management</category>
            <category>business</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test MDX]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/test-mdx</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/test-mdx</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[// Render a YouTube video player]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>// Render a YouTube video player</p>
<div style="width:100%;height:360px"></div>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>maintenance</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Blog Post]]></title>
            <link>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/first-blog-post</link>
            <guid>https://neldivad.github.io/blog/first-blog-post</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet...</p>
<p>...consectetur adipiscing elit. Pellentesque elementum dignissim ultricies. Fusce rhoncus ipsum tempor eros aliquam consequat. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>bruh</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>